<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <title>Direction With Intent</title>
    <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
		<icon>https://directionwithintent.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
    <subtitle>Think Through. Execute.</subtitle>
    <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <updated>2021-05-30T22:24:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://directionwithintent.com/</id>
    <author>
			<name>Nuno Valente</name>
			<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
			<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
		</author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>MV Journal May 17 - May 31</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_7/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_7</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/Banner_MVJournal_banner_7.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;Last week we saw the end of the first legal battle that pitted Epic Games against a technology behemoth, Apple. Fortnite’s owner wants to revolutionize how app markets work and, to that end, made a bold move against the most prominent market makers for mobile applications: Apple and Google. 
While some fight for dollars in digital markets, others try to improve the shopping experience in physical markets. At this side of the pond, a [Sensei] and [SONAE] joint venture opened the first grab and go cashier-less supermarket experience in Portugal following [Amazon GO] lead.
Save a few minutes of your time and dive in at another MV Journal issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#grab-and-go-shopping-like-a-ninja&quot;&gt;Grab and go. Shopping like a Ninja.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#market-wars-with-epic-battles&quot;&gt;Market wars with Epic battles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;grab-and-go-shopping-like-a-ninja&quot;&gt;Grab and go. Shopping like a Ninja.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;may-26th&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;May 26th&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April 2018, at the end of an informal social dinner after a well packed Lisbon AWS User Group Meetup, one of the Spain AWS presenters was checking if his Revolut credit card would be accepted by our payment terminals. My co-organizer quickly pointed out that Revolut had good service in Portugal, but he avoided using his physical credit card almost all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do you pay stuff and get physical money if necessary?” asked the technologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Just using my smartphone as a QR code reader and issuing draw codes for our ATMs with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mbway.pt&quot;&gt;MBWay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AWS technologist looked confused, but most of my fellow compatriots took the statement with a nonchalant demeanour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let me stress that our dinner friend presented bleeding-edge technology from AWS in our humble user group. This is a person that sees innovation daily, and he still looked surprised by our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modernity usually creeps in bits. It takes a while to understand that we are immersed in its hot waters, and when we notice it, it’s already too late to get out. Portugal is one of the best places for validating new technology, and our ATM network and services are an excellent example of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months before our User Group, Amazon was debuting Go. The first cashier-less store where a client just picks what he wants and leaves the store, removing one of the most significant friction points between the customer and the brand. No more waiting for payment in the queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 2021, almost three years later, we’ve seen the first replica of Amazon Go, opening its doors to the public in Portugal. The partnership between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sonae.pt&quot;&gt;SONAE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sensei.tech&quot;&gt;Sensei&lt;/a&gt; , two Portuguese companies, brought us &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.continente.pt&quot;&gt;Continente Labs&lt;/a&gt;. A new cashier-less supermarket store packed with bleeding-edge image tracking systems and weight sensors, picking up client actions and tallying the expense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the technology is impressive, it still has a steep bill attached to it—almost a million euros for 150 square meters that cannot be fully exploited to squeeze the investment. As in most innovations, first-comers pay the price while others will reap the benefits of a mature technology a few cycles in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, this isn’t the first cashier-less store that promises no queues at the end. Another Portuguese brand already had a similar concept store with client tracking and automated payments at the exit. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pingodoce.pt/lojas/pingo-doce-go-nova&quot;&gt;Pingo Doce Lab Store&lt;/a&gt; does the same. In 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeronimomartins.com&quot;&gt;Jerónimo Martins&lt;/a&gt;, the owner of the Pingo Doce brand, opened a bigger store on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.novasbe.unl.pt/en/&quot;&gt;NOVA SBE&lt;/a&gt; campus with the objective of testing and developing new technologies for their brick and mortar stores. The big difference is the way that the client interacts with the products that he wants. You can’t just pick up and leave. You’ll need an NFC smartphone to read product tags and confirm their pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thinks how long the technology of both brands will expand to the remaining stores. Some probably will have to wait many years since a typical supermarket takes 2000 square meters. A single 150 square meter store took 20 Kilometers of cabling. Many smaller stores in large cities are the best target of an upgrade if the experience becomes successful, but the usual Portuguese supermarket will have to wait for some technology breakthroughs. From what we see, Pingo Doce’s trial wasn’t pushed to other stores, but one has to consider that between 2019 and our current day, home deliveries took the lion share of clients and brands preoccupations.
Maybe in a world with less COVID, we can see a renewed interest in physical stores and investments to improve a client shopping experience, but until we are back to fully open and restrictionless days, one cannot see such spending making sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-waiting-game&quot;&gt;The waiting game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A European study puts supermarket queuing times in the podium of waiting with an average time of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acrwebsite.org/volumes/11474/volumes/e01/E-01&quot;&gt;20.2 minutes per shopping trip&lt;/a&gt;. In our experience, we’ve felt that the numbers are pretty generous.
Queueing theory deals with these numbers and ways of making them shorter on average. From roundabouts to the great teachings of Eliah Goldratt on how to defeat the bottleneck, we’ve played this game since the first time that a resource was busy. Wouldn’t it be nice to avoid it altogether?
Cashier-less stores are a pleasant proposition. In and out without a fuss. Go through the checkpoint and get billed at the exit avoiding human interaction with any store employee. Imagine how technology has been removing queues from your life. From bills to the lottery, skip the storefront and go online, avoiding synchronization with other humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why not avoid going to the store altogether?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The COVID pandemic pushed retailers to deploy and improve home delivery services. With many workers furlough or working from home, waiting for grocery delivery isn’t a problem. Supermarket chains can schedule deliveries easily while shoppers are happily waiting. When businesses open again and workers are at the office, delivery hours will shorten for many. Fees will probably get higher for prime time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether we opt for home delivery or visiting a supermarket, we hope that we can forget that shopping queues ever existed in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;market-wars-with-epic-battles&quot;&gt;Market Wars with Epic Battles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;may-29th&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;May 29th&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard to negate that Apple is at the forefront of product development and innovation. Having a device from Apple is a luxury even coveted in Cuba, and having the money to buy it will probably set up back for a big part of your salary or, you probably are in a mid/top tier of wealth earners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some have the chance of holding a piece of Apple’s equipment even at the cost of a kidney, which actually happened with a Chinese citizen, others have a big purse to buy it and even spend more dollars in software.
The near-luxury status of Apple makes everything Apple-related very enticing for businesses. Wheater you are selling accessories or digital goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortnite, one of the most profitable games from Epic Games, was making a bundle selling game passes and in-app purchases such as avatar and equipment skins for almost every game platform.
While the absolute values aren’t public, some estimates point that 1.2 billion dollars flowed through Apple App Store, leaving a commission of approximately 350 million dollars. While everything was working as intended for Apple, Epic didn’t share the same opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple isn’t the only market-maker for smartphone applications, although it controls its hardware and software distribution. Google also has its Play Store, which houses a wealthy library of applications for Android. The difference between both is well-known. While Apple doesn’t allow sideloading applications nor third party markets, Google leaves some space for competition.
Nevertheless, Google’s Play Store has the most extensive footprint in the Android app market, and it isn’t hard to understand why. The brand matters, and client’s put their trust in Google’s products. On the other hand, Google doesn’t help competitors either. They actually penalize third-party stores making them hard to install or even flagging them as unsafe. &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Aptoid&lt;/a&gt;, a Portuguese third-party app market, found it early in their business since 2014 battles with each new Android version. Mulivision’s floor neighbours can tell you a story or two about Google’s behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether in Google’s Play Store or Apples App Store, you have to pay a 30% commission, but only after making a million dollars in Apple’s case. Until then you get a discount rate of 15%. For each dollar that your app extracts from a user, 30 cents go to the market maker. Epic went with the rules initially, but eventually, the company CEO thought it was too much, although it’s a fee found in almost all gaming app markets. On one occasion, Mr Tim Sweeney, Epic’s co-founder and CEO, even suggested that an 8% fee would be enough to make Apple’s and Google’s markets profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Log story short, Epic’s CEO decided to launch a Fortnite version in both markets that sidestepped Google’s and Apple’s fees, but after a few hours, both versions were removed, with Epic being kicked from both stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a company is very hard to take with a friendly demeanour a client’s take stating how much you should make or how much profit is fair, especially when considering non-essential digital goods. But this is precisely what Apple and Google need to defend at the court. Their profit is appropriate, and that the exclusion of third party markets in Apple’s case is for the user benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should make us all even more confused is that Steam, Valve’s digital game store, also asks for the same fees as Google and Apple, but Epic is ok with it, probably because Fornite isn’t on their online shelves. Apple even asked for Valve’s numbers to make their case but was denied by the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to pundits and lawmakers, it’s unclear if any of Epic’s battles will win any Market war, but the probability is low. No date was set, and months will pass before any decision is made public. In between, Epic will continue to push its agenda leveraging &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-56941173&quot;&gt;European Union’s decision against Apple practices within the App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Apple’s also took a swing at another Epic’s moneymaker, but with even more dire consequences for Epic. Epic’s iOS and macOS accounts were about to be closed after Epic’s Fortnite account was removed. One of those is responsible for maintaining the development and support of Unreal Engine. The gaming library is probably the basis for a large chunk of first-person shooter games, and Epic gets 5% royalties from big earners.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2020/8/26/21402443/epic-fortnite-apple-unreal-engine-ios-game-developers-lawsuit&quot;&gt;While Epic took a full-frontal assault at digital giants, it left a broadly exposed flank that can be exploited by its adversaries.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us wait a few months but hoping that greed doesn’t affect most developers and brands that earn their livings from these markets, and some, using endangered libraries.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>MV Journal May 3 - May 17</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_6/"/>
        <updated>2021-05-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_6</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/Banner_MVJournal_banner_6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;Security and privacy. If you ask individuals if they want them, they will probably say yes, but few will actively choose them, leaving the community even more exposed to be exploited by businesses and criminals. This week we take a dive into Apple privacy and government insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#apple-ad-nudge&quot;&gt;Apple Ad Nudge &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#life-hacking&quot;&gt;Life Hacking &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;apple-ad-nudge&quot;&gt;Apple Ad Nudge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017 Mr Richard Thaler and Mr Cass Sunstein got one of those calls that you can’t miss. Well, to be accurate, Mr Thaler failed to pick up the 4:00 AM call from Sweden, and one can understand, but that is another story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prize in memory of Mr Alfred Nobel rewarded their work on a controversial theory. Nudge, which is also the name of their book about the subject, tells us, among other things, that the power of default options can be a massive driver of policymaking without compromising a citizen agency. While, in fact, we might argue that some defaults might be pernicious when the agent doesn’t know all the options, one can appreciate the benefits of good default options. Take, for instance, the organ donor option in your driver’s licence or medical id card. Inertia will regulate swats of citizens to ignore the choice, and if the default selection is “not allowed”, it is proven that a large proportion of citizens will ignore the alternative even though they might be inclined to take the altruistic choice. Switch the onus of negation to the subject, and you’ll get near the opposite result contributing positively to society in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ios-choices&quot;&gt;iOS Choices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time iOS users had the chance of switching their choice regarding ad targetting was in September 2016 when Apple released iOS 10. From that point on, users could mask their presence on the internet by switching a single toggle in their device settings. In December 2020, Apple stated that approximately 20% of users opted out of tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial Nudge here was quite clear. Ad targeting benefited the expansion of the iOS platform, especially from users who, on average, spend much more than users from other systems such as Android. And don’t forget to take into consideration the previous releases that just ignored the user preference regarding privacy. The first iPhone was launched 9 years before. Enough time to grab a significant ad market share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2019, Apple is giving signals of changes around privacy, and this is a subject that gains significant traction from several internet players. Even &lt;a href=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_3/#a-floc-flies-under-the-radar&quot;&gt;Google saw their latest effort repelled by almost all browsers, as you’ve probably read here.&lt;/a&gt;
Although one can’t pinpoint Apple’s true rationale for the change, besides the privacy concern that is publically promoted, it is a development that matches the risk from some other Apple options in the past. For instance, dropping the headphones jack caused a considerable reaction from users and hardware vendors. Everyone agreed that it was a drastic option, even if you were keen on Bluetooth alternatives. Nevertheless, we see some years later that wireless headphones are here to stay, at least for a while, and have become widely adopted by mobile device users.
This time, it will be difficult to lead by example since the most significant competitor isn’t quite interested in taking the same route. Android, being part of Alphabet, will probably avoid berating Google’s ad business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today, 4% of users opted in with the new ad tracking option when the estimates pointed to 10 to 15% adoption, which was already alarming numbers for advertisers. But using the word advertisers dilutes the most significant players that are worrying about this option and leading the pack we have nonetheless than Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It isn’t clear if most Facebook users understand that they are an asset to ad-hungry companies. Whether we are talking about Instagram or Facebook, publicity is the most significant income slice for the company and losing big spenders will impact their value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can speculate that mitigation strategies are already in place by many ad specialists, but Apple claims that it will penalize app developers that try to infringe user privacy options. We can take this as a serious warning since Netflix and Fortnite precedents are still vivid, and in the case of Epic Games, Fortnite’s owner, it is still up for deliberation in American courts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that the “private by default” Nudge will be adopted by many businesses, but the price tag might be too hefty for the end-user. Without a clear path to discriminate user preferences, digital advertising will need to start using probabilistic approaches or even the dreaded “digital prime-time” where buying the best time slots on a UTC frontier will be available to businesses with the capital for mass-market publicity, leaving small business out of user’s sights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is an extreme prediction for the ad market, but the next year will be crucial for the business. With privacy nudges everywhere, from GDPR to the end of third party cookies, it’s going to be read ocean for advertisers and a blue ocean for ad disruptors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;life-hacking&quot;&gt;Life Hacking&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Captain Crunch and Joybubbles.
It isn’t the name of a comic book nor a TV show for kids. The pair of whimsical characters go back to the early 70s when America was still at war with Vietnam. They are known to be the first hackers in the wild, taking advantage of flaws in the AT&amp;amp;T telephone network architecture to make free phone calls.
Those were simpler times, technologically speaking, and hackers (phreakers if you want to be precise), while disruptive to some entities, didn’t present a real risk for citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the ’90s, and incidents become more severe but still without any worldwide impact. Some hacker groups can take control of bank accounts, and penetrating governmental institutions becomes a badge of honour in the community. The sequence of events brings down the powerful bureaucracy of the United States, and laws are passed to condemn agents that conquer unauthorized access to third party systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superpower governments start to get annoyed with kids and hacker ensembles that act like they own the internet. They understand that a new battleground emerges from the globalization of technology and adjust resources to avoid being outgunned by other players. Enigma in the second world war should be an excellent example of how a clear vision of the enemy information flow can decide the victor. Cyberwarfare begins, first without real consequences, only as a spy versus spy competition, at least from the point of view of an ordinary citizen, until Stuxnet is made public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allegedly, Stuxnet was the product of a USA/Israel joint venture to stifle the atomic efforts from Iran but take this with a teaspoon of salt since nothing is confirmed and several specialists made conjectures about the topic. Nevertheless, the final product is a remarkable piece of Software with a very well-defined purpose in a narrow range of equipment. Too much of a coincidence that Iran saw their nuclear program suffer setbacks from an onslaught of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this point on, with the WWW spreading like wildfire, every computer becomes a target, and it’s not just fun and games. Some actors become political activists while others just want to create havoc. In between, criminals loot credit cards and exploit human frailties to steal money from their digital pockets. While mayhem and activism get media attention, cybercrime moves volumes of capital under authorities’ radar using ransomware software. A few variants can be found, but the modus operandi is usually the same. 
Infect the target machine via a known vector
Encrypt data or steal sensitive information.
Ask for a ransom to decrypt the target’s precious bytes or threaten them with data exposure.
Wait for donations.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalguardian.com/blog/history-ransomware-attacks-biggest-and-worst-ransomware-attacks-all-time&quot;&gt;The first one that we know about was delivered by mail in standard floppy disks and with a PO box address to where targets should send the money&lt;/a&gt;. After so many Hollywood films, one can clearly point out the flaw in the plan. How to get money anonymously without leaving a trace?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The combination of ransomware and the advent of cryptocurrencies took the cybercrime business to new heights. Freezing data and systems of a target using advanced cryptographic Software via the normal attack vectors is the equivalent of a pointed gun. Making the target comply with a secure money transfer requires an extra step. Provide clear instructions on how to buy a digital asset and transfer it in a safe and timely fashion to an anonymous wallet on the other side of the world or even in the office next door. That can be quickly done by attaching an extra piece of Software or just a document to help the unfortunate victim. After that, the cybercriminal just has to wait that a successful transfer is made to provide the cryptographic key in exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be a shooting game in the dark and wait for a top-up of the donation box. Automation can deal with transfer confirmation and key delivery, making time for the cybercriminal to be on top of new attack vectors or updating botnets that drag the web, fishing fresh new targets. An this might be the crux of the matter. A slice of the cybercriminals makes random attacks. A computer is a target, whether it is a bank or a hospital. Last year it was documented &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/09/18/world/europe/cyber-attack-germany-ransomeware-death.html&quot;&gt;the first death, suspect of a ransomware attack to a hospital&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May 7. The Colonial Pipeline in the United States, one of the most critical oil transport pipes, suffers a ransomware attack that forces management to close the fuel faucet. In a few days, after the word got public, gasoline prices start to rise, with citizens raiding gas pumps and filling every container at hand. This event took a week and a day to resolve, raising alarms everywhere in the government and the federal bureau of investigation.
DarkSide, the group of hackers who assumed the responsibility for the attack, later made statements that reveal regrets about the incident. With a half-apology, they’ve declared that targets would be scrutinized beforehand to avoid social distress. This was too little too late, of course, but at least no deaths related to the incident were tallied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concerns with this type of random attack are clear, but they raise even more issues when governments only think security threats should be fenced from governmental systems. Private endeavours are the backbone of an economy, and the dimension of some should become a governmental concern as well, speaking in terms of obliging one with the security that the state should provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But has the state the capacity of protecting systems, whether they are within the governmental sphere or not? In 2019 an ex-employee of a Kansas water supply station hacked the system and fudged with the values of some chemicals used to treat the water. The incident could have affected the water supply of thousands of citizens, causing health problems on a massive scale. Incidents with utilities are more frequent and expose vulnerabilities in old and unpatched equipment. Utilities aren’t a sexy infrastructure and an easy target for cyberwarfare. Probably we shouldn’t wait for governmental institutions that sometimes lag with technology deployment at their own sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-defend&quot;&gt;How to defend?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security should be at the forefront of software development and not as a system after-patch. Country critical systems should be isolated from the web until security is taken seriously when developing and deploying newer systems. This has a cost, of course. It will take more time and money to set up safe facilities, usually cumbersome for operations because of the security hops and checks that one has to take to manage them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Max Tegmark is one of the founders of Future of Life. An institution that tries to tackle the important technological humanity endeavours that bring immense benefits but significant risks as well. One of the foundation areas of interest is Artificial Intelligence and the safety of such systems. In a “Making Sense” conversation with Mr Sam Harris, he points out the “security first” mindset when putting humans on the moon. He states that we need to revisit and reuse the same guidelines when developing systems that can backfire, leaving humans in a dire situation.
I would argue that Mr Tegmark could expand those concerns to existing dull technology, ignored and taken for granted by all, but a pillar of the human status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>MV Journal April 19 - May 3</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_5/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_5</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/Banner_MVJournal_banner_5.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;This week it is all about scandals!
We start with the last update from Basecamp, and it seems that everybody is packing up and leaving. On the other hand, a skittish Portuguese Public institution got scared with a Facebook post and shunned the services of a great company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#waking-up-at-basecamp&quot;&gt;Waking up at Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cloudflare-conspiracy-in-portugal&quot;&gt;Cloudflare Conspiracy in Portugal &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;waking-up-at-basecamp&quot;&gt;Waking up at Basecamp&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;may-1st&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;May 1st&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;Mr David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Mr Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt; carved an extraordinarily successful company from the boom and bust of the dot com era.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;, formerly registered as 37Signals, was founded in 1999 as the typical digital agency focused on the shiny web world that was about to burst. Nevertheless, the company survived through tough times and rebooted itself in 2004, leveraging the work of Mr David Heinemeier Hansson, or DHH as he is known on the web, that culminated in the Ruby On Rails first release. A good mix between European and American stock took the company to stardom and created a Siliconish culture that many developers sought to work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full remote company that opted out of the Unicorn stables and kept its core values, avoiding what the founders thought would be unsustainable growth and unreasonable demands from investors. And it worked.
Ruby On Rails became one of the most successful web development frameworks, and version 7 was about to hit the public repositories, &lt;a href=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_3/#ruby-on-rails-7-ever-given-moment&quot;&gt;as we mentioned some weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;. 
Basecamp becomes a bastion for Open Source within the Ruby environment and sets the tone for remote work in the software development market. Along the way, they &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books&quot;&gt;publish several acclaimed books, one being featured in the bestseller list of the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. The company strives to share what it takes to become another Basecamp and how to avoid the pitfalls of the startup era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software at Basecamp is opinionated. Obviously, you don’t expect that technology expresses its feelings about the way that it is used. The expression is based on how the Software was designed to steer and encourage end-users to work with it. Opinionate Software imposes work pathways and rules intending to create frictionless experiences. Ruby On Rails is a great example, and the “On Rails” part says it all. The first versions of the framework were groundbreaking. Making a web application with a LAMP stack require the developer to keep architecture traceability from the top of his head. Each iteration could yield a different way of doing things which hampers the integration of new developers of even day-to-day maintenance. Rails leverage the dynamic features of Ruby to establish a working path for every project. A developer could be utterly ignorant of business rules, but diving into a new codebase would be like a walk in the park and a very familiar one indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Company leaders and hired developers were aligned on product and software development topics which helps pushing forward Basecamp’s agenda. To work at Basecamp, you should be opinionated and with product development skills. From designers to customer support employees, Basecamp built a team that was well integrated with the culture and promoted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without disconnecting themselves from Basecamp and Rails, Mr David Heinemeier Hansson and Mr Jason Fried become very active online, promoting their political and business views mixed with Basecamp’s company culture topics and spreading their feelings online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Apple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/dhhapple.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to Zoom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/dhhzoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;,there is always a target that they could point out in the Twittersphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t unusual that their employees matched their beliefs, not only strengthening their points of view but inadvertently mixing business with pleasure to a point where one can not distinguish the borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-dei&quot;&gt;Enter DEI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Jason Fried made an appearance in 2017 at an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/magazine/201709/jason-fried/2017-inc5000-diversity-in-the-workforce.html&quot;&gt;Inc’s article&lt;/a&gt; where he suggested that his company didn’t make the necessary efforts to promote a diverse environment, but the work already started, and they couldn’t wait for a transition. They need to be the drive of it.
This was a clear signal to the Diversity, Equity/Equality and, Inclusion movement.
Some years have passed since that piece was produced, and last year, a new employee took this matter with his own hands and started a DEI Council to push forward some ideas into company policies. As usual for DEI diehards, it was necessary to shovel out old skeletons and make apologies public. An old Basecamp name list was made visible to everyone at the company as an example that something must be done.
Some senior employees built a list of funny client names in their spare time as comic relief from the day-to-day business issues. Eventually, the list becomes an uncomfortable joke for some, and after a while, the jig was up.
Whether the issue was solved by the company or by the passing of time is unclear, but it served its purpose to address the alleged uninterest of the leaders in the new DEI council. Escalating small issues as the root of all evil was the first step, and this time, Mr David and Mr Jason thought that it was time to intervene.
While their intervention assumed the blame of a name list that was fundamentally wrong in MR David’s view, it wasn’t something that should be blown out of proportion and dismissed the issue with some rationality. The reaction was building up within company borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking his own time and a few weeks later, Mr Jason published a new company policy that “societal and political discussions” were banned from their office place, meaning, their Basecamp software instance.
After coming down to this point in the article, the reader might already see what happens when trying to stifle opinion in an opinionated company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first backlash was internal and brute to the point of trying to get action from HR against company founders.
Doubling down on the new policy, Mr David took a huge management decision and offered severance packages to everyone that didn’t agree with the status quo from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you can find a list of tweets from multiple Basecamp ex-employees when writing this piece. More or less, a third of the company left Basecamp, but the problem goes beyond virtual walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zachwaugh/status/1388190748189802501?s=12&quot;&gt;Zach Waugh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/georgeclaghorn/status/1388131009531719680?s=12&quot;&gt;George Claghorn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kaspth/status/1380616358266871810?s=20&quot;&gt;Kasper Timm Hansen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dylanginsburg/status/1388199059983413257?s=20&quot;&gt;Dylan Ginsburg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the names are active contributors to Rails and Ruby. They influence the development community. Although it’s straightforward for a company like Basecamp to replenish its human resources, it’s tough to recoup the social capital built on top of the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next weeks are crucial for Ruby on Rails and Basecamp, and it would be unfortunate if this event accelerated the graph that &lt;a href=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_3/#ruby-on-rails-7-ever-given-moment&quot;&gt;we’ve featured in a past article&lt;/a&gt;. Ruby on Rails and the Ruby community still have a lot to pour down into the technology zeitgeist, and it would be a shame to see that a minor or unexisting DEI issue might affect the tech community cohesion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cloudflare-conspiracy-in-portugal&quot;&gt;Cloudflare Conspiracy in Portugal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;april-29th&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;April 29th&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do know that Portugal is a drop of water in the technology ocean. Featuring a few Unicorns in our borders is a proud thing to have, but we shouldn’t be fooled by the reach of technology prowess.
Trusting in well-established companies with a proven track record is a good rule of thumb, and when the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ine.pt/xportal/xmain?xpgid=ine_main&amp;amp;xpid=INE&quot;&gt;National Statistics Institute&lt;/a&gt; hired &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;/a&gt; to help with the security and availability of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://censos2021.ine.pt/&quot;&gt;Portuguese Census site&lt;/a&gt; they were making a good choice, one thinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cloudflare-even-in-portugal&quot;&gt;Cloudflare, even in Portugal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November 4 2020, Mr Matthew Prince made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/eastdakota/status/1323947883201142786?lang=en&quot;&gt;poignant tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/mattprincetweet.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tagging the Portuguese Prime Minister and Mr Paddy Cosgrave. Mr Matthew is the co-founder and CEO of a well-known company, Cloudflare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the Portuguese Government wasn’t following through with some promises that it made to bring tech talent to Portugal.
It remains unclear if this was simply an American entrepreneur having a taste of Portuguese bureaucratic inefficiencies or if we saw backstage promises that couldn’t be fulfilled. The aftermath of the social exposure was dealt with behind doors, and nothing was spoken publicly afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward six months and Cloudflare is hiring heavily for Lisbon. At the time of writing this piece, we saw seventy positions available. This is a significant investment in the Portuguese technology environment and brings a small country closer to companies with a planetary scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cloudflare-why-not&quot;&gt;Cloudflare. Why not?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the previous segment into our attention is essential to consider NEI’s option. Cloudflare isn’t only a big company that could provide good service to NEI. It is also an important company to retain and bring talent from the tech world. We can’t tell for sure that the decision was taken with political backstage action, but even if it wasn’t, it was a good option for the services that NEI’s required and for the Portuguese partnership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-conspiracy&quot;&gt;The conspiracy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we can see with more frequency, conspiracies and false news spread like wildfire. A single Facebook post that we aren’t linking here to avoid distributing even more bad content of this type was replicated and explored by several actors. Portuguese Census data was being transferred and stored outside national borders.
If this was true, it was a big slipup of the Portuguese Government and a clear violation of the European GDPR.
NEI’s reaction to the conspiracy was to end Cloudflare’s contract even after both explaining publicly that private data wasn’t stored in Cloudflare’s servers. They even pointed out that for Cloudflare services to work correctly, it is better to use edge locations instead of relocating connections to a data centre on the other side of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-technology&quot;&gt;The technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare’s provides services for availability and security. The idea is to provide secure links to an application and keeping it up and running even when some addresses suffer high traffic periods or direct DooS attacks.
Static assets are cached, but dynamic content is outside of Cloudflare’s control. This means that user input is also outside of Cloudflare’s services, and client servers should be responsible for persisting any user interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-law&quot;&gt;The law&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unclear at best.  In fact, there is the chance that Portuguese data flows to servers outside of national borders while in traffic. This should not be a problem for GDPR, but grey areas might squeeze some precedents if the case is taken to the courts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do hope that rationality prevails and NEI’s can reinstate their contract with Cloudflare. There isn’t any technical reason that makes this a dangerous or risky deal for Portuguese data. On the other hand, we are still in murky GDPR waters, and we could get a hand slap from Brussels bureaucrats nonetheless. If that happened, it would break the trust with a great company that opted to invest in a country in dire need of foreign capital.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>MV Journal April 5 - April 19</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_4/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_4</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/Banner_MVJournal_banner_3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;It seems that we are living through a slow world reboot. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ever_Given#2021_Suez_Canal_grounding&quot;&gt;traffic of massive boats can flow through international waters unencumbered again&lt;/a&gt;. Pharmaceutical companies trickle jabs to every nation with gradual global adoption revealing minor bugs here and there. Excluding &lt;a href=&quot;https://ourworldindata.org/covid-vaccinations&quot;&gt;early adopters that are far ahead&lt;/a&gt;, we can see a new major version of life rolling out with ease, bringing us to another edition of the MV Journal.
Yes, you are right. This is sooner than expected, but we are syncing our releases with Multivision’s newsletters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-old-facebook-leak-that-is-new-again&quot;&gt;The old Facebook leak that is new again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#mv-journal-follow-up&quot;&gt;MV Journal Follow-up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-old-facebook-leak-that-is-new-again&quot;&gt;The old Facebook leak that is new again&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a frequent Facebook user, you’ve probably got the warning that some of your private data were leaked, and I’m not (only) talking about the most recent word on the grapevine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my readers still didn’t care about social media at the time
 but Harvey Jones and José Hiram Soltren presented a &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.csail.mit.edu/mac/classes/6.805/student-papers/fall05-papers/facebook.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; in 2005 where amongst several topics they referred the potential privacy issue with the information posted on the platform. Their work included an analysis of user posts, publicly available at the time, from more than 70K users from different schools. The information was obtained with a simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_scraping&quot;&gt;data scrapping script&lt;/a&gt;. To better situate the reader, we need to remember that Facebook was designed primarily for the USA’s Ivy League colleges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years later, the company started allowing search engines to index profile pages and soon tried to monetize user information about rented Blockbuster videos. The business idea set back Mr Zuckerberg a  total of 9.5 million dollars after a class action suit that invoked the [Video Privacy Protection Act], and it was the first actual learning moment for the company. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_wants_to_be_free&quot;&gt;Information wants to be free&lt;/a&gt;, but if it isn’t yours, you should lock it up as hard as the IT allows it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2021 and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techrepublic.com/article/facebook-data-privacy-scandal-a-cheat-sheet&quot;&gt;many leaks later&lt;/a&gt;, we get another warning from almost every online tech media outlet. 533 million users got their phone numbers exposed from a breach that was allegedly reported and closed in 2019. You’ve probably “liked” a link to this report on your Facebook page.
Facebook claims that the data is old, and the attack vector is closed. The story says that someone or a group of someones exploited the phone search feature and collected the data but looking for any Facebook warning about the issue at the time yields no information. If one pushes back the search a year early, we see that Facebook dropped the feature in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claiming that the data is old serves only as an excuse for the media. And a weak one indeed.
Facebook is a global platform. Considering the last decade of operations and counting the leaks that were made public,  it is quite possible to create rich data sets with user timelines, valuable for criminal or commercial endeavours.
We also know that Cybersecurity is a challenging topic and drives a trillion-dollar industry. Even the safest systems in the world are not impervious to data breaches, but what we usually get from platforms such as Facebook are IT blunders or plain irresponsibility with data management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-shadow-of-shadow-profiles&quot;&gt;The shadow of Shadow Profiles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of data breach isn’t limited to registered users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large enterprises made of multiple mergers and acquisitions eventually face the single sign-on battle. It is usual to pull user data from every information system to get a picture of the company employees and access requirements to create partial profiles to bootstrap the process.
Facebook took a similar path to build user profiles for non-users. If you recall, handy features to sync contacts from phonebooks and mail lists started showing up a decade ago in every mobile device. They allowed merging social profiles with your contacts, enabling quick access to any app using a single index that matched mail address with phone number with LinkedIn profile and with, of course, your Facebook profile.
Even if your privacy concerns keep you on the sidelines of the social media arena, you might have been leaked as well, thanks to the contacts of your closest friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-now-what&quot;&gt;And now what?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still living through the legal infancy of global digital corporations. To be fair, legal systems worldwide aren’t equipped to deal with technology pace and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-australia-46463029&quot;&gt;state legislation is flawed&lt;/a&gt; to say the least. The EU, amongst other state ensembles, are taking the first steps to penalize poor data security and management, but one cannot see systems like GDPR as a final option. It is still up to the user to take responsibility for their data and avoid oversharing. Data technology literacy needs to be taken seriously and taught to younger generations in Instagram, Snapchat and Tik Tok bubbles so that pandatum leaks don’t impact users’ and their virtual neighbour’s lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mv-journal-follow-up&quot;&gt;MV Journal Follow-up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last week featured a few topics worthy of mention, but I want to open up a new section on our esteemed MV Journal series.
Media is fast, too much nowadays. It burns hearts and souls with pressing topics but discards them as quickly as they are read. Retractions, corrections and follow-ups are rare to be seen, and we want to pay our dues to the latter, hoping that the first two don’t happen so soon in our publications.
So without further ado, let’s pick some of our previous posts and see what happened since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mv-journal-premiere&quot;&gt;MV Journal Premiere&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular edition got an update before “going to the presses” but left one point untouched.
In the piece &lt;a href=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_1/#mr-bezos-switches-gears&quot;&gt;Mr Bezos switches gears&lt;/a&gt;, we’ve introduced the new Amazon CEO but at the expense of a vacant position in AWS. Mr Andy took the CEO baton, but there is already someone to fill in the seat.
Mr Adam Selipsky currently leads Tableau Software and will replace Mr Andy in May. He’s not an outsider. With an 11 year stint at AWS before moving to Tableau he will come with a challenge well cut for him. Bringing his deep understanding of the cloud business that propelled Tableau to a spectacular exit to the Salesforce conglomerate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;march-24th-until-april-6th&quot;&gt;March 24th until April 6th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last edition revealed the new user tracking agenda from Google in the piece &lt;a href=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_3/#a-floc-flies-under-the-radar&quot;&gt;A FLoc flies under the radar&lt;/a&gt;.
After deploying their experiment, Google had to wait for the backlash, but it didn’t come from the user world.
Vivaldi, Edge, Brave and Mozilla already made their statements, and they will not fly with Google’s FLoC. At least for now.
Most of the companies showed a lack of interest or even repudiated the technology, pledging non-adoption. For now, this is great for the end-user that will get a wide array of options to cater for their privacy needs. Nevertheless, I don’t think that this is going to be the end of it. Unless browser technology keeps being subsidized by joint ventures of large tech companies, eventually the money will become an issue, and as we’ve seen, only large corporations such as Microsoft and Google can keep dollars flowing into developers hands. We are probably going to see developments in the near future so stay tuned to our releases.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>MV Journal March 23 - April 06</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_3/"/>
        <updated>2021-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_3</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/Banner_MVJournal_banner_3.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;With all eyes and hearts deeply enthralled with the Ever Given fiasco and the Covid-19 season that never ends, it was hard to find those tech gems from these last two weeks. Loosen your seatbelts because this will be a slow and scenic ride, with mildly interesting facts, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ruby-on-rails-7-ever-given-moment&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails 7 Ever Given moment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-floc-flies-under-the-radar&quot;&gt;A FLoC flies under the radar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ruby-on-rails-7-ever-given-moment&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails 7 Ever Given moment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title is too obvious, but it’s hard to avoid the snafu of the moment.
Quite recently, the Ruby On Rails team announced that version 7 was bound to be released in one of the most important events of the community, &lt;a href=&quot;https://railsconf.com/&quot;&gt;RailsConf 2021&lt;/a&gt;. The conference, held since 2006, gathers a large swath of technology enthusiasts.
Unfortunately for the overall community, interest in the framework is dwindling down, but not so much that one can predict a “the end is nigh” scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;https://ssl.gstatic.com/trends_nrtr/2431_RC04/embed_loader.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt; trends.embed.renderExploreWidget(&quot;TIMESERIES&quot;, {&quot;comparisonItem&quot;:[{&quot;keyword&quot;:&quot;ruby on rails&quot;,&quot;geo&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;time&quot;:&quot;today 5-y&quot;}],&quot;category&quot;:0,&quot;property&quot;:&quot;&quot;}, {&quot;exploreQuery&quot;:&quot;date=today%205-y&amp;q=ruby%20on%20rails&quot;,&quot;guestPath&quot;:&quot;https://trends.google.com:443/trends/embed/&quot;});
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although one can see the framework popularity becoming a problem, it still musters technology giants such as Shopify, GitHub, Airbnb, VMWare, and many more. Even if no new large projects come to fruition, products and services will not evolve or maintain themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 7 promises much, but we’re not here to review the release. It would be best if you took a peek at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edgeguides.rubyonrails.org/7_0_release_notes.html&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; for that information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in all open source projects that depend on large communities of contributors, sometimes they rely too much on single players and put too much faith in due diligence from every project. Open Source can be unruly, even with professionals dedicating their time and resources to greater causes and community respect. The component development distributed approach spreads the work and the risk. Still, any large project should take steps to avoid crumbling when a minor project decides to pull out, even when there is a legitimate reason.
Of course, that core development of the framework isn’t significantly impacted since platform and framework developers tend to avoid external dependencies changes while meddling with lines of code at their own machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true problem comes when the merchandise needs to be delivered to alfa and beta testers via public package repositories. Each installation pulls the latest gem or latest changes directly from the source code repository. Community testing will not find every potential bug but smoothes many rough edges that a core developer team can’t test in due time. It’s even worst when the automatic test suite doesn’t pass from continuous integration and development tools, preventing any package from even partial testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Vendorizing” might mitigate the problem, but it will not solve the puzzle. The term with unknown origin but stemming from the Ruby community refers to the technique of including stable versions of the dependencies within the source code of a project. It would help early adopters to keep testing a technology, avoiding rogue dependency changes. The process would require compiling from the source code instead of using the usual package channels. The drawbacks are obvious. At release time, core developer teams would need to check if their dependencies are still kosher while removing them from the repository before creating a new pristine package. More process and bureaucracy isn’t appealing but sometimes are required at some professional levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment of writing this piece, the release date changed to “to be announced”. Let’s hope that Ruby on Rails floats again soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-floc-flies-under-the-radar&quot;&gt;A FLoC flies under the radar.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ad targeting its one of the biggest business weapons in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/fang-stocks-fb-amzn.asp&quot;&gt;FANG’s&lt;/a&gt; club panoply.
The Ads business per se is valued at numbers that few humans understand. Still, they are marketed to advertisers at even larger values when the Ad publisher states that it can optimise publicity investments targeting the best audience for their product or service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ad publishers and buyers primarily relied on the “third party cookie” to achieve the promised optimisation. The simple technique of saving small blocks of data in the client machine within the browser space allows for smoother web surfing when talking about first-party cookies. Still, it also opens up tracking of the user when it comes from a third-party provider. The simplest example possible can be described with the fictional visit to www.foo.com. Within www.foo.com, which leaves its first-party cookie, there is an Ad for bar.com with the right ( with the browser permission ) to drop a third party cookie. Every site with a bar.com Ad will understand where the user has been on the web from this point on. Enter Ad targeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning, third party cookies became a privacy concern, and even in the ’90s, they were considered prejudicial for the safety of the end-user. Imagine a world without HTTPS where all traffic flows open to interception.
In the last decade, we’ve seen efforts from browser brands to clean up this door, but when Ad publishers own or invest in browser development, it’s hard to understand how this would work without the force of law. In Europe, we’ve seen what that might bring. After the GDPR’s enactment, web sites decided to avoid the European customer altogether, albeit few. The majority added the mandatory form that asks the user to select which third party cookies you want to accept and their purposes. If you’re a European user, you’ve already felt the user experience degradation everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 30, Google flipped a switch for 0.5% of Chrome’s user base on restricted geographies. On top of the third-party cookie, Chrome will build the user FLoC ID and send it back to advertisers in the first phase of the technology with real users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FLoC stands for Federated Learning of Cohorts. Considering a low-resolution explanation, the FLoC ID will replace individual tracking with third-party cookies using group signatures. The group signature should be transient, but it will store your online behaviour in a piece of data that matches other users behaviour. A signature will fall in multiple cohorts, allowing advertisers to target groups of users with similar interests and behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is much to be said about the technology and if it really works on the user behalf, but everything points out to more significant problems with groups of users while avoiding singling out a specific user. To get a better picture, we advise a visit to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WICG/floc&quot;&gt;official repository&lt;/a&gt; and a broader analysis from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2021/03/googles-floc-terrible-idea&quot;&gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. Although they present a dire future for the web, we want to focus on the user choice issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-experiment&quot;&gt;An Experiment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine that a corporation or government decides to experiment with a new way of delivering a vitamin to a broad spectrum of the population. They choose to embed it into the water distribution of some locations and see how it goes.
While some readers are already appalled with such a proposition, this is what frequently happens on the web. Vitamins aren’t a water feature, and tracking isn’t a web feature. Nevertheless, social experiments like the one that Google is doing with FLoC are a dime a dozen. After opening the FLoC feature toggle, Google gave no warning to users that are a part of the experiment.
Even using “experiment” is mainly abusing the word. It seems that FLoC will stay for some years, and we should see it as it is. A technology trial.
One might not care about tracking and even accept paying the price to avoid random Ad spam, but assuming that the software that runs on a user machine can switch behaviour without user consent is more difficult to understand.
There is a way of opting out of the experiment but at the cost of crippling existing features. The user needs to disable all third-party cookies explicitly. If your privacy concerns are serious, you’ve probably made this decision in the past, but consider users that rely on single sign-on portals and need to lose unrelated facilities to avoid experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first FLoC flight is already in the air, and time will tell if the technology stands, but users should be informed that they are part of worldwide social experiments, and be provided with a lever to exit the ride at any time.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>MV Journal March 9 - March 23</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_2/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_2</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/Banner_MVJournal_banner_2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;The second edition already? And what a couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ovh-roof-was-on-fire-and-we-dodged-that-bullet&quot;&gt;OVH roof was on fire, and we dodged that bullet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#nfts-digital-uniqueness-paying-off&quot;&gt;NFTs Digital Uniqueness paying off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ovh-roof-was-on-fire-and-we-dodged-that-bullet&quot;&gt;OVH roof was on fire, and we dodged that bullet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;march-13th&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 13th&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time, I need to have a talk about backups at the office, and if you ever worked with me, you’re already familiar with the rhetorical:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;

    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What if our data centre burned to a crisp?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other reasons, I also use the “What if Jonh gets hit by a car?” but I digress. Some years ago, I found out that I wasn’t that original and, this particular type of problem is already known by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor&quot;&gt;Bus Factor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 10th, I bet many System Administrators got immense heartburn after losing pings to their cherished machines and learning later that their data sublimed after one OVH Strasburg data centre got utterly destroyed by fire while a second one was heavily damaged in the incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/tweetovh.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the fire was still running, the whole Strasburg site had to be disconnected, putting every machine offline and out of businesses reach.
You can find OVH’s statement in the following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ovh.ie/news/press/cpl1786.fire-our-strasbourg-site&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that Multivision is an OVH client, but fortunately, we weren’t significantly affected by the incident since we only had a few development machines at that location.
We can only wish the best of luck to every business out there that might stop to a halt after this tragic incident and a speedy OVH recovery as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, even if you didn’t get affected by this accident, the event should be enough to remind us all that even the smallest business should always keep in mind the 3-2-1 backup rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 data copies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 types of storage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 copy offsite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nfts-digital-uniqueness-paying-off&quot;&gt;NFTs Digital Uniqueness paying off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;march-11&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our premiere issue, we’ve covered [Bitcoin’s value skyrocketing] (https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_1/#more-fuel-for-the-btc-fire), creating digital millionaires in a few weeks, not to mention the people that are saving valuable digital hashes for future speculative movements.
This week, we will cover another type of digital asset that is taking creators and investors attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Mike Winkelmann, also know in the digital art industry as Beeple sold one of his digital artworks for 69 million dollars with the famous auction house Christie’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;And what the proud owner got?&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This: &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlineonly.christies.com/s/first-open-beeple/beeple-b-1981-1/112924&quot;&gt;Everydays - The First 5000 days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But make no mistake. The owner didn’t pick up a physical art piece. The lucky buyer received a data file from the transaction, notwithstanding a unique digital file minted as an NFT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/tweetbeeple.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, Mr Beeple. We get the feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep up and make the best of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;non-fungible-token--nft--a-primer&quot;&gt;Non-fungible Token ( NFT ), a primer.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;69 million dollars is a ridiculous amount of money for most mortals, but this wasn’t Mr Beeple’s first rodeo selling an NTF. A month before this record-breaking number, another original Beeple was sold for 6.6 million dollars of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethereum&quot;&gt;Ether&lt;/a&gt;. The piece was initially sold last year by Mr Beeple himself for the modest amount of 66.666,66 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what’s a Non-fungible Token?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the ubiquitous Blockchain, the technology allows a user to uniquely identify a collection of bytes making him the de-facto owner of the collection and possible signed copies. Although you can create infinite copies of the same byte collection, it’s always possible to establish the provenance of such a collection and even the transactional history of the ensemble querying the underlying NFT blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the previous explanation in mind, it is easy to understand how to map this digital property set to the physical world. Assume that the author of a book only signs one hundred copies of is the first edition. A first edition might turn the printers for thousands of book copies, but only a fraction will have that valuable scribble of your favourite author.
NFTs allow for the same type of scarcity in the digital world. An entity can create a set of digitally signed copies that reside in the implementation of a Blockchain. From that point on, the copy can switch hands with a typical transaction in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;art-but-what-else&quot;&gt;Art, but what else?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When writing this article, I explained the technology to a friend of mine in a casual conversation, which made him remember something very similar. He pointed out that the NBA was doing something similar with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbatopshot.com/&quot;&gt;Top Shot&lt;/a&gt; business. He described that collectors bought “moments” instead of physical cards, giving the impression that it was a brand approved “scam”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some light digging, I’ve found out that they are leveraging NFTs for this endeavour in a partnership between the NBA and Dapper Labs, a well-known software house that develops games using Blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My take on NFTs would be precisely this. Every collectable that we might think can be translated to this medium, but not only that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the games World of Warcraft or Fortnite, where weapons and avatars can be digitally minted. Game collectors could actually own the first sword that brought down Kel’Thuzad or a unique avatar for official competitions of a Battle Royal event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, we are still some years from having digital assets on par with physical objects, but I would not be surprised if my son’s son invests in NFT markets daily.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>MV Journal Feb 22 - March 9, Premiere</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_1/"/>
        <updated>2021-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/mvjournal/mvjournal_1</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/Banner_MVJournal_banner_1.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;First, let me give you a warm welcome, reader. This is the first installation of the semimonthly MV Journal article series. This Direction With Intent post series is sponsored by &lt;a href=&quot;https://multivision.pt&quot;&gt;Multivision&lt;/a&gt; and will be part of the official communication for employees, clients and any stakeholder with enough patience for the author. Every couple of weeks, I’ll be writing about the tech-related news and events that sparked our interest or had a global impact on the industry, trying to make a clear divide between facts and opinion. I would also like to thank Multivision for the trust deposited on my content here at Direction With Intent. Although my opinion isn’t necessarily representative of the company and administration, it’s part of the human ensemble that constitutes the company. Every word will be written with the required respect for the reader and responsible for carrying the company brand value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutting to the chase, here are the topics of this first issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#more-fuel-for-the-btc-fire&quot;&gt;More fuel for the BTC fire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#mr-bezos-switches-gears&quot;&gt;Mr Bezos switches gears&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#media-battles-down-under&quot;&gt;Media battles Down Under&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-fuel-for-the-btc-fire&quot;&gt;More fuel for the BTC fire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, I bought my first Bitcoin. At that time, you could carry a wallet in a standard thumb drive and using a third party for storing a Bitcoin was noobish at least.
My plan was to get a few of those sweet digital hashes and go on a shopping spree in the now-deceased Silk Road dark web marketplace. I didn’t even know how much I would need for whatever illegal stuff I could buy without getting arrested for it :) but feeling like a Black Hat was a thrill.
My plan failed, and I didn’t buy anything, but some months later, I sold my last BTC for around 100€ and stating to my friends that this bubble should blow up at any moment. And I had a rationale. The protocol doesn’t scale to allow everyone to use it as a debit or credit card with a payment being processed in a matter of minutes or seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…I made a profit, and I should be happy with that…Fun times they say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a decade and a few “pop” false alarms later, Mr Elon Musk decides to go “all in” and buy 1.5B of Bitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/coinbasebtc.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this piece, BTC rallies again for another all-time high.
Although Mr Elon isn’t the single responsible for the previous colossal increase in value, surely he had a considerable impact on the virtual currency trading exchanges making him a whale in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that but from now on, Tesla will accept payments in BTC. 
Yes! It seems that some Teslas will roll out from the factories after presenting some cryptographic hashes to the dealer. Fun times indeed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;update---no-mountain-is-too-high-for-bitcoin&quot;&gt;Update - No mountain is too high for Bitcoin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this is the first MV Journal release, there is some lag between the written pieces and the date we publish them. Below we can still see that the BTC value at Coindesk is pushing the limits, and even with some less than kosher tweets from Mr Elon, one can still imagine that the rally is far from ending this soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/stillrising.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mr-bezos-switches-gears&quot;&gt;Mr Bezos switches gears&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/104961749-Jeff_doordesk.png?v=1529477304&amp;amp;w=1400&amp;amp;h=950&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year was 1994. You can see a young Jeff Bezos on top of what serves as a desk but, in reality, is a door supported by four by fours, with a metal reinforcement at the angles.
Since the beginning, Mr Bezos pushed the company with a groundhoggian philosophy of meeting every new day like day one. That also means that frugality was a keyword when considering any investment. Some decades later, many offices still sport desks made of doors as a homage to those initial years.
Nowadays, Mr Bezos leads a world conglomerate that ships almost everything you can imagine while being the IT backbone of other mega services such as Netflix and Outsystems. On the side, he still holds the Washington Post, keeping the dying business of the press very much alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The move announced this week shouldn’t be a big surprise for many, although a much delayed one. Since 2016, Mr Bezos created a small circle of trusted execs to help run the empire’s day-to-day. Everyone was waiting that the CEO torch falls into their hands. Andy Jassey was the lucky one if you think that a 24/7 job with thousands of workers relying on your decisions means luck.
Mr Andy, responsible for the massive success that AWS is nowadays, will hold the keys of all Amazon aspects, from retail to the cloud. A big responsibility for sure and with challenges that Mr Bezos will happily delegate for the following years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Bezos is not going anywhere. He lifted himself to the chairman position, but the audience guess is that he’ll be there for the tough days that eventually will meet the company as he already warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my part, I hope that his efforts focus on the space industry with Blue Origin. Mr Musk has pushed the boundaries of this endeavour, making everyone feel that he doesn’t need competition to accelerate towards the future, but this might not be the case when the business solidifies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Multivision, we wish well to Mr Bezos and his transition, hoping to see some of those Blue Origin ships delivering packages to Mars colonies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;media-battles-down-under&quot;&gt;Media battles Down Under&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time, we see some doubtful tech legislation popping up here and there on the globe—some with good intents but usually grounding themselves on ill-informed politicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australia doesn’t fall behind, and everyone still remembers the TOLA Act, rammed into the Aussie parliament in 2018. A proposal that makes IT companies break their encryption and potentially develop security holes, well known as backdoors, 
“Let’s just make Australians safer over Christmas,” said Mr Bill Shorten, leader of the opposition at the time. It’s not a wonder that the IT sector still remains unconvinced. Just ask Atlassian for their thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time we see another controversial law, to say it at least. While it doesn’t seem as dangerous as the TOLA Act, it will significantly impact the average internet information consumer.
The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accc.gov.au/focus-areas/digital-platforms/news-media-bargaining-code&quot;&gt;News Media Bargaining Code&lt;/a&gt; passed the Aussi parliament on 17 February. The law targets the American IT tech giants Facebook and Google, requiring public deals with media agencies to keep the ability to share and maintain links to their media outlets. This law initiative aims to rebalance the news industry, making the aforementioned content distributors liable for paying repurposed content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this piece, the table has been set and played. Facebook left the proverbial Aussie news building while Google forged deals with the largest news providers. From now on, links to Australian news content will be “restricted” within Facebook. Take my test in the image as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/nopes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, you can still share your favourite Australian topics with your groups of friends on Whatsapp. Let’s see for how long.
On the other hand, and with much more at stake than Facebook, Google accepted paying up, keeping their business intact and even increasing its Google News content portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;global-shakedown-an-opinion&quot;&gt;Global shakedown, an opinion.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This decision’s ripples are already being felt in other countries, with some elected officials supporting similar initiatives at their borders. We might even see, country by country, a follow up of the same tactic, appeasing local news businesses and voters. The most significant impact will probably come from the EU, which has successfully implemented its creative taxation proposals for companies operating within the Schengen space. The most recent victim is Netflix and other services with a similar expression in the digital streaming domain. In the same political lingo, the consumer is warned that the tax protects local content production. That remains to be measured and seen, as in most cases.
The same premise applies to the new Aussie law. Nowhere is written that the funds channelled from the tech giant will be used in the news sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should expect lawmakers to create fair conditions for the consumer and product or service provider, but in this instance, the final consumer is left out of a B2B deal, where a conglomerate of businesses says that another company is using their product or service without their consent. In fact, the product or service is massaged to be relevant in the content providers’ rankings that benefit from the shakedown. It’s served in the businesses on volition, using less than kosher tactics to make them the top of the search or the most shared article of the hour. Instead of paying for the dissemination service, it is the other way around. The dissemination service pays for the privilege of providing content shards and referral traffic to the source.
While it can be said that Google will also use the full content within one of its products, Facebook will create a social sharing black hole for the current Australian affairs. Independent and amateur content creators and providers will fill in space without asking for money in return. If one of the final objectives is to protect the consumer from false or biased content, the effect will be precisely the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the TOLA act, we see that the Australian government needs support from the new generations that understand the integrated tech world. Not entirely, but better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;update---facebook-falls-in-line&quot;&gt;Update - Facebook falls in line.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After showing a hard hand, Facebook nevertheless adjusted to the regulation. To be fair, Facebook’s action triggered the Australian parliament to revise some of the law’s most draconian options. One of the most important ones allows for a quick Facebook escape button. The platform will reserve the right to block any disputed content that doesn’t fall in its negotiation perimeter and avoid getting caught with its back against the wall of a forced business.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>On Alarm Dumb Numbness - A Primer</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/software-engineering/alarm-dumb-numbness-primer/"/>
        <updated>2020-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/software-engineering/alarm-dumb-numbness-primer</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/lanl-rods-too-close.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;If you’re like most of the human workforce on this planet, you have to wake almost every day at a specific time, adhering to a more or less well-defined schedule. To help you with that particular event of the day, you’ll probably recruit the help of an “alarm clock” to keep you aligned with your job time tables and to avoid a wrong turn on your employment status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your “alarm clock” blares in the morning, you have a few options to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=izWCU4Y61o4&quot;&gt;deal with it&lt;/a&gt;, but the end game is quite clear. Get up and take some action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a clear objective for this “alarm”. Stop your sleeping cycle. And usually, it is successful. Your senses can’t avoid it if configured adequately in terms of sound/vibration unless you’re affected by some ailment that makes you unconscious or insensitive. The reaction time may vary, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most common artificial “alarm” of the modern world, but this isn’t an alarm (hence the double commas around the alarm word) no matter what they say. Bear with me, please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the most trivial alarm that a human being can get without any artificial supplement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Queue jeopardy think music.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, that’s right.
Pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get your hand to close off a flame, and your sensory receptors will send a loud and clear message straight to your brain, making a roundabout in your spinal cord, and back again for that burn familiar feeling.
This is the most basic alarm that a human can get. Many abnormal external stimuli that put you in danger or directly violate your body integrity, assuming that you don’t have any health condition preventing you from sensing them, will generate an almost instantaneous alarm forcing you to retreat from the pain source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without boring you much more on the primer, from my examples, we can extract two types of event that require an alert system, but only one of those is an alarm. In one situation, an external alert is necessary for some action to be taken. The second one refers to an abnormal event that triggers an internal alarm when a boundary is about to be violated or already was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before going further, it is important to distinguish both since they get confused in the day to day lingo. On System Design and Engineering, the conversation needs to be clear and concise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the “On Alarm Dum Numbness” series of posts, I’m going to delve into alarm management, hopefully, providing a thought structure that can make you avoid some of my past mistakes when designing alarm systems, or to be more precise, ad hoc sets of alerts and alarms that eventually fail to serve their purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re curious about this post image, check &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencemag.org/news/2017/06/near-disaster-federal-nuclear-weapons-laboratory-takes-hidden-toll-america-s-arsenal&quot;&gt;this article from Sciencemag&lt;/a&gt; explaining how a disaster was about to happen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Code does not wear company colours</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/software-engineering/the-code-does-not-wear-company-colors/"/>
        <updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/software-engineering/the-code-does-not-wear-company-colors</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/jruby_1600x800.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;After a few projects and some nasty burns, eventually, any engineer understands that the code doesn’t care. It will compile, or it will be interpreted, it will run, and it will fail or succeed, but in the end, it will not care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been out and about in the community, you’ll probably read or listen something along the lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/g/mailing.freebsd.hackers/c/DylcvbPzW5g?pli=1&quot;&gt;“It is not X programming language job to stop you from shooting your foot. If you so choose to do so, then it is X programming language job to deliver Mr Bullet to Mr Foot in the most efficient way it knows.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code will do what is programmed to do, but it really doesn’t care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when your sprinkle your company name, that you value so much, on variables, classes, components, agents and even on your bare metal machines (Use the Cloud Luke), code still doesn’t care. It will not read clearer, run faster nor debug quicker even if you try to dress it with your company colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And up to this point, you think that I’m right but not adding much. You do know that code doesn’t care and singularity is far ahead. So why should you bother with names…and why this rambling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’ll end it with a word: Rebranding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop’s the mic and leaves the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You can find Terry Lambert’s original quote within the linked thread. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>On Diderot's Effect Applications</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/product/on-diderots-effect-applications/"/>
        <updated>2020-10-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/product/on-diderots-effect-applications</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/luxury_living_room_300x300.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;The Diderot Effect is an application of belief reinforcement on a self-identity stereotype within the context of consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now take a breather. Too much content in a few words, for sure. Let’s unpack this before going further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-walkthrough&quot;&gt;A walkthrough&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1988, McCracken ( what a name ), Grant David, from Illinois University, inspired by one of Diderot’s essays, coined the term while drilling down some of the aspects of a consumeristic society in his &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/199188.Culture_and_Consumption&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;.
The effect is based on the story written by the French philosopher Denis Diderot, where he explains that the mere appropriation of an exquisite gown was the seed for a spending frenzy in luxurious items for his house. The sentiment that took him to disperse his modest fortune in those items gained momentum each time that a new piece was introduced. Later in a cathartic exercise, he spilt all of his feelings on paper, more as an act of punishment than an artistic creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From McCracken ( the name! ) analysis, he distils the Diderot unit as an ensemble of products where the consumer maps his self-identity into. He also notes that the transition from a Diderot unit to another one doesn’t come easy. There is significant surface tension before a person dives into another spending spree since it correlates with the consumer accepting a change in his self-identity.
When was the last time that you’ve changed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not go into detail about McCracken’s (I did mention that this name is awesome right?) work, but I will inspect the effect, explore some of its characteristics and try to devise strategies that a Product Manager might employ, increasing his chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a spiral of consumption in a wide variety of products isn’t something easy to achieve. However, we can find instances of the effect with relative ease in our social circles if not in one’s own life.
Take adult (and sometimes the odder young-adult) nostalgia that makes us crave for familiar feelings from a fuzzy past, but without the constraints of that era of course. Creating a retro-looking house that hides modernity behind the design is a way of reinforcing that sentiment that we were meant to live in another era.
For example, consider &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smeg.com/&quot;&gt;Smeg&lt;/a&gt;, the Italian brand of vintage-looking kitchen appliances. Buying one 50’s style toaster might be the beginning of a hefty and ever-growing credit card bill on house appliances. You might find other brands like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ziyandappliances.com/&quot;&gt;Ziyanda&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kitchenaid.com/&quot;&gt;KitchenAid&lt;/a&gt; to get a matching kettle but without avoiding the bank account set back. And good luck finding original vintage items in working conditions for reasonable prices. An overview of online auctions will set you straight before going into that route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t think this is only a rich person’s game, a way of bankrupting the middle class or squeezing innocent French Philosophers. Many sports aficionados usually spend a considerable amount of cash on merchandise and sometimes memorabilia from his favourite team, whether the circus is football, basketball or formula 1. The subject wants to show support and love for the team as much as he wants participation in some way.
He’s a real &lt;insert sports=&quot;&quot; team=&quot;&quot; here=&quot;&quot;&gt; supporter, and it shows.&lt;/insert&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoraonline.pt/&quot;&gt;Pandora Jewelry&lt;/a&gt; where bracelets can be built upon affordable prices, charm by charm.
Although the brand instils the feeling that the consumer creates a unique piece that eventually might exchange hands as an heirloom, sometimes it just looks like you’re carrying a case study of the Diogenes syndrome on the wrist ( just my opinion of course ). Buying a bracelet with a charm is just the beginning of a commitment, and you’ll find a new charm for every characteristic of your being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tattoos?  I’ll stop here since you’ve already got the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, to understand the facets of this phenomenon, we need to grasp a wider frame of the aspects that influence a consumer decision to absorb a Diderot unit.
You need to understand that Diderot’s tale doesn’t start with an exquisite gown in his back. The gown was just the first step concerning the consumption phase. Before that, it began with one or more rooms already filled with the luxuries that he denounces or a fictional vision with the same features.
Well before his first purchase, or some friend offered him the gown ( there is some contention about the origin of the garment ), he already had the chance for appreciating things that would make his study a renaissance king’s room. He had an image of the place where he would like to live. An image created with intromissions on the lives of high placed ones. It could be a vague and stylized idea but enough to fill his own accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here lies the first not so easy trick in a Diderot’s entrapment. The creation of an image that can be split into a puzzle for piecemeal acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/stylish_ensemble_300x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although publicity and marketing would be rare things in Diderot’s time, nowadays they are indispensable tools for most of us PMs.
Consider those innocent images of a stylish laptop on a working desk, surrounded by other good looking items that might not even be at the same technological level. That old looking leather bag? The vintage camera? The open and scribbled moleskin? You can buy all on the online store link right beside the image. Why not add to cart directly from the picture? One by one until you can reproduce the image at your own volition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of this ideal image is that it can be mixed and matched with other elements. It can become your unique image, instead of being a copy that any other consumer can get. The entrapment needs not only one view of the desired environment but a variety of elements for a wide range of collages, each one depicting the beautiful moments that the consumer will experience with a similar set of items.
The ensemble exclusivity attribute will avoid the feeling of making a collection of mass-produced items that only require perseverance and a deep enough pocket in exchange for a vulgar lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-diderot&quot;&gt;Digital Diderot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within digital worlds, we can see more and more applications of these principles to keep the user acquiring more virtual goods, coin by coin. Although we associate this behaviour to younger demographics, this is only because we are growing with the technology. I wouldn’t be surprised to see retirees with disposable income, become escapees in virtual realms for fun and glory, flashing their cyber bling, renewed at each software upgrade.
Another very appealing aspect within the digital environments is the fact that you can be much more volatile regarding the self-identity that you want to imprint on the remaining participants. Cheaper acquisitions that provide sex, ethnic or even race mutations. The liberty to move between Diderot units is much larger than in reality, which benefits not only the digital market creator but also the products created to live within that market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-long-tail-strikes-again&quot;&gt;The long tail strikes again.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the niches. Those are always a good target for the strategy. Take the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese culture fans will drop their savings into remarkable pieces of serial-produced art of their favourite characters.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy-paste my last sentence and replace Japanese culture with Marvel, DC, Star Wars, Pokemon, et al.
Some of them are authentic art collections, I’ll give you that, but it’s almost trivial to take advantage of the effect on the fans.
Royalties and deals for the copyright are expensive? You can always get creative like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qwertee.com/&quot;&gt;Qwertee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-novelties&quot;&gt;On Novelties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you only have a single product? A novelty type.
Take as an example a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gopro.com/en/us/&quot;&gt;GoPro&lt;/a&gt; camera some years ago or the latest abs machine from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qvc.com/&quot;&gt;QVC&lt;/a&gt; as novelty examples.
Applying the effect on this type of product is a bit harder but not impossible. I’ve already provided one of the most important conditions that you need to respect. Your product needs to mingle almost seamlessly with an assorted set of products, and ideally, it should be possible to do it in different contexts. A GoPro camera is an excellent example. From competitive fishing to skydiving, the camera is the same, although the lifestyle and accessories differ. Diderot units can be very different, but the way that GoPro’s marketing campaign placed the camera in different stories making it an essential piece that increases the reward of the experience is an example to copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/school_300x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine an innovative hand sanitizer bottle. If you’re trying to appeal to parents and kids, maybe you can introduce it on a picture where the classroom material such as pens, glue, pencil and sharpener are all over the table and shared by his friends. In the mix, add a colourful hand sanitizer so that the dirty play stays on the table and doesn’t travel back on the child’s pockets to your pristine home&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I’m creating a very speculative scenario, but the principle is that your novelty product, in this case, can be selected for the student lifestyle. It’s a valuable item that will have a positive effect on the usual ensemble of school paraphernalia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exercise can be repeated over and over for multiple scenarios and targets with the same objective. Create a picture where your product merges with the background and don’t be afraid of spreading the publicity between products. Insert your product in already existing Diderot units and take advantage of the spending momentum of the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;complementary-goods-not-really&quot;&gt;Complementary Goods? Not really.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Economist would suggest that this is a direct application of a (complementary good)[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Complementary_good], but a more observant thinker notices that it isn’t a requirement and probably isn’t a good fit for the term.
Just as an example, consider rolling tobacco and papers. The demand for the first is highly correlated with the demand of the second, which in turn will create a price correlation as well. This is an almost perfect example of a complementary good.
While the correlation between these two products is evident, even considering fringe uses of both, a direct correlation between complex sets of products that benefit from the Diderot’s effect isn’t required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to create a complementary good ( and it would be harder to coordinate product requirements ), but you should compose the environment where the perceived value or even the return of investment of your product will go up when seen within a collection. And this last sentence segue to another aspect that doesn’t need to be present, but it will help for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tag-team-for-the-win&quot;&gt;Tag-team for the win&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re up to date on your pop-culture trivia, you might recognize the next one. 
Did you ever notice that charm of a staged house or indeed just a bedroom in an IKEA store?  On the set, if you inspect each item closely by itself, you start losing the interest from few of the more average things, but if you take a few steps back and see the ensemble, it appears that the whole gets an added layer of glossy veneer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The Cheerleader effect)[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cheerleader_effect] provides a hypothesis with a more sexual tone in the experiments which I’ve tried to avoid in my example. The effect is definitely controverse since it isn’t replicable in any conditions, but I wouldn’t discard it so soon since the result is real on some cultures and contexts.
The idea seems simple, and it’s mostly an advertising trick. Ensemble images that include your product in between some other attractive buying options will boost the subjective attractiveness index that someone attaches to it. It should be possible to exploit it with some simple A/B testing techniques, and fine-tune the index to the final consumer group.
Unmistakably, you should avoid the pitfalls of trying to mingle products for different classes of consumers. Don’t try to take pictures of your hand sanitizer in a Ferrari. Your effort to make it more appealing will be blatant and will backfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jumping-diderot-units&quot;&gt;Jumping Diderot Units&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To finish this analysis, there is another aspect that a product manager should understand when introducing new products that don’t shake the paradigm and are only marginal improvements of existing ones.
Considering Diderot’s tale again, one can see clearly that the gown didn’t introduce an objective improvement in the author’s life. One might argue about some minor enhancements regarding comfort but accepting the story as it is, even Diderot’s grants that his old gown was a more superior fit for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Why didn’t I keep it? It was used to me and I was used to it. It molded all the folds of my body without inhibiting it; I was picturesque and handsome. The other one is stiff, and starchy, makes me look stodgy.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the first act of change was a trigger for his final sorrow. In between, he got the room that fitted the gown. It wasn’t something new that he introduced in his environment but a change of the old for the new.
We don’t know if it was an impulse buy or even a gift, but it could be left aside and ignored so to avoid disruption in his house. He accepted the change and identified himself with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming back to our study, let us consider that your newly introduced product actually brings an objective improvement that is measurable, and you can point it out to your potential customers. Let us imagine a futuristic desk light that not only adjusts automatically to the ambient light but also follows your vision field whenever you move your head to inspect if someone is creeping beside you while you’re reading a horror story in your bedroom. It even will turn itself on and off according to your eyelid patterns. Cool hum? You see a benefit right from the start comparing it with your night lamp, but unfortunately, the design doesn’t match your old furniture style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the consumer considers if a single appealing item, apparently useful, but not useful enough to disrupt his furniture state of affairs.
To burst the surface tension, you’ll need to appeal to the inspirational instinct of the buyer.  He needs to see the change at that moment and invest in the modernization of his environment. As I’ve mentioned earlier in the text, the luxury pieces in Diderot’s room had already been seeded by existing high society tastes. Those are the ones that you’ll need to take from the current world around you to create the most bleeding-edge image where everything around the desk light is a requirement for life itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating an inspirational context around a product is evidently tricky, and so it is that making the consumer jumping between Diderot’s unit ( in the real world where he has skin in the game ) it’s one of the most challenging manoeuvres to do when it comes to his real self-expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summing up,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Understand that a Diderot unit needs to be seeded in the mind of the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The digital selves are an excellent target for consumers since the notion of self-identity is prone to volatility. No skin in the game makes this possible.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The long tail can become a marketeer target again with this strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Novelties can take advantage of the effect as well as long as the product manager is willing to share the stage with others.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Complementary goods isn’t a good description of elements in a Diderot unit. They don’t need to be directly correlated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Exploit the Cheerleader Effect with A/B  testing of your image ensembles.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Resistance to change is inherently human, so don’t expect to break momentum but try to use the consumer inertia in your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This one was written amid a pandemic. The hand sanitizer exercise isn’t innocent. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Hortator, an Antiquity word for the modern times</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/product/hortator/"/>
        <updated>2020-09-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/product/hortator</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/hortator_1771x958.png&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;Hortator, a Latin word meaning “one who encourages.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header and teaser image&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; use was kindly authorized by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cngcoins.com/&quot;&gt;Classical Numismatic Group, LLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Antiquity and until the end of the XVI century, the Galley boat dominated the Mediterranean. One of the most visible aspects of this type of boat is the parallel lines of rows on each side. Inside the Galley, you would find the manpower that pushed the behemoths between Mediterranean shores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Galley structure was diverse, but a usual architecture for large ones would put the oarsmen below the deck or below an elevated platform that supported officials and troops.
Two or more lines of men on each side, in a coordinated effort, propelled the ship with the sweat of the brow.
It was a strenuous and muscular work for sure and anyone that tried to row, even on a static one, knows that it isn’t a child’s play. Anyone that had the chance of experiencing a canoe ride, whether using a row on each side or a single one with two paddles, notices that body coordination is as essential as the strength that you put on the push of the paddle. The row should hit the water with the thinnest area possible and exit the same way. In between the surface area of the paddle should face the force of the water and push it behind.
Not an easy skill for a  single rower. Now multiply that by 10, 30 or even 170 like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trireme&quot;&gt;trireme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Roman empire heyday, when their navy still meant something, (although not that much) and mainly during wartime, galley rowers were lower-ranking roman citizens, colonists and freeman. Rowing within this type of boat wasn’t a task that you could throw forced labour upon. The coordination of the job required training, discipline and equilibrium between lines. In dire times when citizens weren’t enough to fill the seats, drafting slaves would be the last option and rarely done. The oarsmen should be focused on the mission of the boat and committed with the general effort. If a large group of able men wasn’t committed to the ship’s goal and became distressed with the mission, it might mean a disaster waiting to happen.
Greeks showed the path on how to staff a Galley. Romans followed. 
But as you might imagine, even with rigorous row training, coordinate so many hands required ongoing supervision and direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Front and centre, between the two lines of men, you would find the Hortator. The maestro of oarsmen. As stated at the beginning of this piece, Hortator is a word with Latin origin, and it’s best translated as “the one who encourages”. You’ll find few references to the function and some other names such as Pausarius.  But for the intrepid Mediterraneans, it fits the job spec perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His mission was to mark the pace of the row, set direction and execute complex manoeuvres with some type of musical instrument for coordinating row stride. Greeks were known to use the flute, but there aren’t many Roman depictions of the oarsman coordination. Nevertheless, Hollywood imprinted the image of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ax7wcShvrus&quot;&gt;drummer&lt;/a&gt; marking the pace that you’ll also find corroborated by more reputable sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it was impossible to adjust each man speed and row. Lines should be well versed in the technique and muscle trimmed for endurance. Strength equilibrium couldn’t be planned ahead by only organizing lines at the beginning of a trip. The effort of a line needed to be averaged out and the Hortator would need to understand which side to favour with slight delays between each stroke while keeping a good momentum. Understanding the levels of energy of the Galley crew was fundamental for reaching any port without exhausting the oarsman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it is quite probable that an Hortator would find himself with a scarce view of the sea around the ship and would have to rely on the orders of the captaincy officials combined with is internal positioning ability. Even with a less protected structure were rowers and the Hortator would be exposed to open sky, his attention needed to be divided between the top brass orders, his positional awareness and the performance of the rowing crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine all of the above amid a battle.
Speed would be critical on these moments, but with short bursts at a time or else no energy would be available for close engagements after boarding enemy ships. Victory or defeat could depend on the energy reservoirs of the Galley oarsman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve bear with me up to this point, I hope you’ll also found a set of characteristics that are essential for the newcome product leads or even for intermediary leadership positions were junior management is put up to the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The process should be as simple as a combination of sounds that mark the pace.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Technical teams on the trenches need a guiding force that can coordinate the effort consistently without adjusting each member at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Moments of high speed should be in short bursts, and only when the time to market means war.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stamina and strength need to be balanced.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vison is hampered on all sides. Your internal compass is fundamental.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hortator is definitely a word that should be recycled for our modern times and a title befitting to the successful leader that strives right where the action takes place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://auctions.cngcoins.com/lots/view/4-T3UPI/hadrian-ad-117-138-as-25mm-1109-g-12h-rome-mint-struck-circa-ad-129-130&quot;&gt;Tail side of the coin (Hadrian. AD 117-138. Æ As 25mm, 11.09 g, 12h. Rome mint. Struck circa AD 129-130. Galley with five oarsmen left, hortator at the stern. RIC II.3 1306&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Balancing your (good) beliefs with the user needs.</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/product/balancing_your__good__beliefs_with_user_needs/"/>
        <updated>2020-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/product/balancing_your__good__beliefs_with_user_needs</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/model_T_1909_feature_1600x1012.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;“If I had asked people what they wanted, they would have said faster horses.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Henry Ford ( not really )&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time you’ll ear this one (or a variant of) in a discussion for some in-house innovation project that requires guidance whether from the armchair or crowd. It poses as the checkmate move from the belief side of the argument, uttered by a product executive, manager and defended by those without the decision responsibility, where the hubris is strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget the sentence’s author and focus on the argument itself ( it’s always the best option ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it really possible to create something amazing for your potential users that could be a paradigm shift on solving one or even more of their problems and doesn’t require any input from any prospect? Or maybe something more humble but still a change for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final user priors aren’t a requirement to build a successful product. Examples of ideas from the ether abound, and it will not be hard to find grand narratives of individualistic creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the idea fails fast. This is a good scenario for everyone but don’t think that it is over yet. “I’m just ahead of time” and “just you wait and
see” will be your pause button of the discussion. “I told you so” will be the play action in a far future when something reasonably similar makes the cut. Authorities will excuse themselves of failure using this rhetoric. This one is oh so pernicious because the listener might fall for the narrative fallacy trap and start believing that the messiah is real.
In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/840.The_Design_of_Everyday_Things&quot;&gt;“The Design of Everyday Things”&lt;/a&gt; you’ll find an excellent example but I will not spoil it. Take a look and get back to me if you find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is always a but right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For developing products, services, companies or truly world impacting ideas, that aren’t only ideology, you don’t need and you shouldn’t play probabilities from the armchair. You can eschew random choices and skew your path in the direction of the best available scenarios.
How to do it? There is enough literature to help you with that and I would add very little to it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/13348394-nuno-valente?shelf=product-syllabus&quot;&gt;My product syllabus&lt;/a&gt; reading list might be overwhelming at first but I would point as a starting point &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/762542.The_Four_Steps_to_the_Epiphany&quot;&gt;“The Four Steps to the Epiphany: Successful Strategies for Startups That Win“&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ratio of one success for each ten tries that Steve Blank mentions should be enough of a deterrent to avoid going all in with your future product. Due diligence may help avoid that one to ten and make it a miserable three in ten but surely you can see the better deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be the victim of your belief in the survivors. Avoid the product hero who’s tunnel vision doesn’t see failure in his path. Go find your clients before they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://quoteinvestigator.com/2011/07/28/ford-faster-horse&quot;&gt;There is no evidence that Henry Ford said or written those words.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Procrustean Beds of Product Management</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/product/avoiding-procrustes-bed/"/>
        <updated>2017-04-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/product/avoiding-procrustes-bed</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/peg_1600x800.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;In the Greek Mythology, Procrustes posed as a gentle caretaker, offered accommodation to any passing traveller. After an invitation for a satisfying meal, he provided a good night’s rest in his exceptional bed. Procrustes described it as having the unique property that its length exactly matched whomsoever lay down upon it. What Procrustes didn’t volunteer was the method by which this “one-size-fits-all” was achieved, namely as soon as the guest lay down Procrustes went to work upon him, stretching him on the rack if he was too short for the bed and chopping off his legs if he was too long. (Adapted from Procrustes — MythWeb (http://www.mythweb.com/teachers/why/basics/procrustes.html))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a Product Management position, one can imagine the many procrustean beds that are built for the private residents, i.e., engineering, quality assurance, operations, sales, etc. or for the passing traveller such as prospect trials, consultants, brokers and, existing clients. Let us refer to them as internal if they are to be fitted for in-house stakeholders, or external if they “accommodate” visitors that aren’t part of the company inner circle.
In this series, I’m going to focus on the external ones and mostly derived from my experience in B2B environments. The ones that may hinder revenue goals directly and create friction in the overall evolution of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prospect client’s trial is a moment of utmost importance and, especially when a product or service has a broad and/or complex feature base. It doesn’t stand for itself. It needs an attentive caretaker that invites the freshly arrived visitor to have the best possible experience and, that can steer him on how to take advantage of the available amenities. Eager as we are, to make an excellent first impression and, to close the deal in the shortest amount of time ( because trials always have a cost ) we invite the user to feel at ease and at the same time we push him to experiment our star features. With the least amount of effort, we show him how to achieve our product promised outcomes. While the caretaker and the user roam around, showcasing the product end to end and iterating over the feature spectrum, we fall into the mistake of force fitting the client to the feature, whether the use case applies or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it should be expected of a product team, we want and need to be creative. We seek inspiration in every problem that we face but sometimes, repeating empty metaphors such as “thinking outside the box”. And regrettably, we try to find solutions on the spot, for the prospect client workflows, habits and, tools, that are allegedly defective, unorganised, inexistent, &lt;insert another=&quot;&quot; problem=&quot;&quot; here=&quot;&quot;&gt;. On the other hand, a small void or even a domain that we’ve managed to exclude from our road-map can bring havoc when a client merely hints the fact of nonexistent work in that regard. Instead, we should take our notes and seclude our selfs, for a moment, where we can summon our creativity and muster our planning abilities towards a well-designed solution. On the spot, thinking and instant client fitting is the moments where we start amputating the prospect expectations and with the best of intentions in mind but ignoring the prospect client true needs and creating product fragilities. Doing this we fall into an uberous mind trap. Let’s delve into one type of this situations. The dreadful and pernicious Workaround.&lt;/insert&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Workaround&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a well-known term in the Engineering class and many times used ad nauseam. Whether it is the best option at a time of need, laziness, schedule compression, damage control or just a temporary patch. It is a well-known term in the engineering class and many times used ad nauseam. Whether it is the best option at a time of need, laziness, schedule compression, damage control or just a temporary patch. A seasoned Software Engineer evidently used it on several occasions and sometimes wakes a night, shivering with the memories of some that still work on a machine somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Product Development, the Workaround has a very similar set of characteristics. It is some process or small addition that will leverage an alternative pathway of one or more features to attain, what we believe to be a quick win. Sometimes with the objective of solving an unexpected user need or capricious desire. Sometimes it’s a cover up of an edge case that the product team did not address correctly or just ignored because they’ve fallen into a pseudo-statistical fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Workaround trigger usually occurs in a commercial or technical tour of the product. May it be a sincere question that has a genuine need behind or a more technical person that wants to show off his wits. Occasionally can be a snarky remark that may compare his current work environment or another tool that he tried recently with our own, and something is definitely missing in his eyes.
The fear and anxiety of not being able to entertain the user, makes us create a parallel thread with a request that the product team scramble the issue searching a way to meet our client expectations. It should not be a problem if at that moment a backlog entry is dutifully filled with a good picture of the issue, that popped up from the conversation, and a reasonable amount of time is taken to consider the proposition. It is a problem when we bypass our product development processes, and the proposed solution involves small feature adjustments that didn’t pass a thorough impact analysis. It is a problem when even avoiding the most minor alteration, it is the result of a collage of one or more features, or maybe, just making use of a feature quirk and painting it as a fully fledged product of human ingenuity. Unfortunately, the Workaround, most of the times results in a non-fluid and/or semi-automatic action plan, requiring the user to withstand some pain or to exert himself to do the same thing that he did or have seen in action before. At the exit of the Workaround, we claim victory if a significant amount of work that the user already does in a streamlined fashion or seen it being executed in the same way can be achieved in our product. We think that we’ve kept the user going, but we don’t see that the user is limping on its way. It may take just a small extra effort to vindicate the capabilities of our product but at the cost of an amputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the attentive and sharp reader, another Procrustean Bed can be found A Posteriori. At the exit of the Workaround and this one with the bed and victim roles switched. This one can kill our product vision and eventually our product. Remember that for the Workaround to be put in place, some small change in our product had to be made. Even when we’ve just managed to pipeline a feature output to another as input, and with some caretaker good will. We’ve adjusted our product to fit that particular prospect or even client need at that precise moment in time without measuring the consequences of those actions. Expectations were created, and new plumbing was added disregarding our architecture, use cases and requirements. To do this, we’ve amputated, rearranged, bypassed and plug it again changing our product morphology. Again, with the best of intentions, to show how exceptional is our team and product. If we exit the Workaround multiple times, it is granted that our product will die in the bed that was made with our client’s hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Workaround is avoidable, and it should be considered an anti-pattern in product development and management. It is damaging for our client prospects, and it is deadly for our product. Take the necessary precautions when you meet with the prospect of a Workaround and make time for fixing it before the product vitality seeps out from all of those newly created ins and outs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know more Procrustean Beds in Product Development and Management? Leave your comments and let’s have a chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Procrustean services and products on the wild&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading this piece one might wonder that no procrustean bed should be a success since it destroys vital parts of the client work, team, company, etc. The reality is quite different and a quick inspection of our surroundings with this thought in mind will show us that sometimes people jump into those beds and accept the punishment in exchange of some promise of greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is an excellent example of a procrustean bed. In this type of services, critical mass has a bandwagon effect that, most of the users aren’t even forced to lay their content on it, while amputating themselves in colorful headlines that the arbitrary 140 character limit can contain. All of them with the fear of missing out the short exposure and afraid that they will not be a part of a vaporous and fleeting zeitgeist.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>An Island and a Cloud.</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/opinion/ground_and_cloud/"/>
        <updated>2014-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/opinion/ground_and_cloud</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/island_1600x800.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-prison-more-like-apple-island&quot;&gt;Apple Prison? More like Apple Island.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, give or take a few months, I’ve changed my work and home machines to Apple systems, abandoning the mixed Windows/Linux environments that accompanied me since high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a quick change fueled by a couple of teammates and the fact that I’ve bought an iPhone a few months earlier. All my Windows machines were dead or in need of repair, and I was just sick of the finicky Vista that was installed by default in my current machine at that time. Those were dark times for Microsoft OSs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change was made, and some months later, I was sold entirely to Apple Software and Hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite things about Apple is the seamless integration of all its products. Connecting my iPhone to my MacBook Pro and easily sync my data between devices, even though iTunes isn’t the best interface to accomplish my syncing needs. Also, the iCloud option for backing up my “mobile data” is noteworthy, although one needs to keep the data hygiene for the free tier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I’m a victim of the mid-2010 MacBook Pro, but even so, the combination of Apple software and hardware bring a level of reliability, far above average. Recently, I also boasted of my 127-day uptime to my teammates that usually restart their machines now and then. I know that any *nix user out there will claim even longer uptimes, but with a maintenance cost that I don’t want to pay every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I own a late-2013 MacBook Pro with retina display, 512 GB SSD drive plus a DDR3 memory total of 16 Gb. Obviously, this isn’t a machine that the everyday user will take advantage of, but for an I.T. professional like me, this is undoubtedly one of the best machines that my money could buy. Add the current Apple option of upgrading OSX free from charge, and you have a system that can last for four or more years without the need for a drastic and expensive upgrade. As my fellow Software Engineers out there, I love to tinker with my hardware and software occasionally, but that’s it. My machine is to work on, and not to bring me extra work just to keep it updated and running smoothly. I have joy and fun hacking away…But I would instead not do it every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I need any piece of software for my tool belt, I just hit a few search queries, and the App Store provides. Even though I don’t actually know the people and processes that Apple uses to accept a new App in their store, I always have a sense of security of the available products. Having at least a primary barrier against mediocre software prevents the application spam that other vendors suffer from their so-called openness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because of the above reasons and so many more, many people would say that Apple software is evil for creating a prison that they cannot leave or decorate on their terms. In my opinion, this is not really a prison, but an exotic island where I can live happily without the diseases spreading on the continent. As a bonus, I can live knowing that the environment is cared, groomed and curated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;above-and-beyond&quot;&gt;Above and beyond&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No man is an island” is a well-known quote and truth. We need to communicate and interact with others to grow, evolve, and produce something that everybody can be proud of. For this to happen, we need to leave our beautiful Island and interact with the harsh environment out there. In this area, I need to champion Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Drive/Docs combination is fantastic, for me, my team and, several stakeholders of the projects where I’m currently committed to. The aforementioned pair brings a powerful tool to keep our product backlog stories, specs and assorted meeting minutes. Documents are edited concurrently between me (under the hat of team lead), a designer team account and a product owner. All these while ideas float around the meeting table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drive accommodates much storage giving us the sense that it is an infinite local share. I just hope that Google invests in improving Docs and Drive interfaces up to the level of most of Apple software. Now and then I need to restructure my Docs and Drive area, but the current interface surely needs refinements and a good UI/UX boost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gmail is widespread, and Inbox is a step forward in solving the current email hell. My personal mail account is Gmail, and the company where I’m currently working has Gmail from their beginnings. I can’t remember a day that Google cloud services failed and caused embarrassment on my company services and processes. Add Google Chat on the mail interface and instantly kill many unnecessary email exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So “Google” reads all my emails? No problem, my friend. If I need to pay those services only by receiving targeted publicity (in a very discrete manner), then please do. Avoid sending me those ads for car rims that I do not care and sell me the smallest pocket wallet on the market. In the middle of that insurmountable pile of data, I’m a male 25–35 years old that is a geek and sports lover. My personal data is protected by numbers that grow every day just as though a flock survives predators with sheer confusion of Agile movement and bird count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-environment&quot;&gt;My environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monopoly is a game that I loved to play when I was a kid and even nowadays is a well-spent night with friends, but it is very dangerous in the real world. I hope that none of these companies can achieve a market position that can dry all of their competitors completely, but right now I choose to spend some years in this lovely Apple island with a Google cloudy sky.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>JRuby / JVM encoding flags</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/programming/jruby-jvm-encoding-flags/"/>
        <updated>2013-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/programming/jruby-jvm-encoding-flags</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;https://directionwithintent.com/images/jruby_1600x800.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, I was developing a couple of extensions for &lt;a href=&quot;http://logstash.net/&quot;&gt;Logstash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my input extensions connected to a SQLServer via JDBC driver and it all worked fine in my OSX machine. But then, an evil Red Hat Enterprise server appeared, took over the control of my processes and started to mess with all of my good JVM configurations (some of them, I didn’t even know that they existed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some suffering, anger and hunger that all debugging processes bring, I’ve found an ancient JVM flag that my evil Red Hat server changed, just to see me cry, after several bad relationships with an assorted number of encodings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sun.io.unicode.encoding=UnicodeBig (good OSX)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sun.io.unicode.encoding=UnicodeLittle ( evil Red Hat)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loading up my JVM with -J-Dsun.io.unicode.encoding=UnicodeLittle saved the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you ever want to check your encoding flags just add this to your JRuby script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;require 'java'

java_import java.util.Locale
java_import java.util.Properties
java_import java.util.Enumeration
java_import java.lang.System

{assorted code}

p = System.getProperties();
keys = p.keys();
keys.each do |key|
  value = p.get(key);
  puts &quot;#{key} : #{value}&quot;
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this script, you can print all of your JVM instance flags. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>