<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    

    <title>Direction With Intent</title>
    <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
		<icon>https://directionwithintent.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
    <subtitle>Think Through. Execute.</subtitle>
    <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <updated>2017-04-16T21:59:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://directionwithintent.com/</id>
    <author>
			<name>Nuno Valente</name>
			<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
			<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
		</author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>Persuasive Design: Using Advanced Psychology Effectively
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0414201716/"/>
        <updated>2017-04-14T20:17:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0414201716</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Persuasive design isn’t evil. It’s a tool, and like any tool, it can be misused. However, with the right research and thoughtful application, it can be a valuable addition to any designer’s toolkit. Toptal designer Bronwen Rees explains how using persuasive design, social and psychological principles can be used to influence user behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>What Do WebLogic, WebSphere, JBoss, Jenkins, OpenNMS, and Your Application Have in Common? This Vulnerability.
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1111084412/"/>
        <updated>2015-11-11T08:44:12+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1111084412</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;By @breenmachine “What? The most underrated, underhyped vulnerability of 2015 has recently come to my attention, and I&#39;m about to bring it to yours. No one gave it a fancy name, there were no press releases, nobody called Mandiant to come put out the fires. In fact, even though proof of concept code was released…”&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>This DIY Wireless Keylogger Fits Anywhere, Looks Like a Wall Charger
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1109092826/"/>
        <updated>2015-11-09T09:28:26+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1109092826</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;The “KeySweeper” is a tiny, arduino-powered wireless sniffer that captures data sent by your wireless keyboard to its receiver. That’s right—it’s a keylogger, and it doesn’t have to be plugged into your computer to work.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How to Build a Portable Hacking Station with a Raspberry Pi and Kali Linux
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1031172936/"/>
        <updated>2015-10-31T17:29:36+00:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1031172936</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Cracking Wi-Fi passwords, spoofing accounts, and testing networks for exploits is all fun enough, but if you want to take the show on the road, you’ll want an easily portable rig. Enter Kali Linux and the Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Learn React.js: Ridiculously Simple Forms
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1010175239/"/>
        <updated>2015-10-10T17:52:39+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1010175239</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;So – you’ve got the hang of React, and you’ve even built a little app. But after making your app look nice, you remember that you also need to make it work. And that’s when you start searching for form libraries. First you look for tools to structure data and event flow. Then you shift focus to libraries which reduce repetition in form components. And while you’re at it, tools which validate user input would certainly help.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Understanding Support Vector Machine algorithm from examples (along with code)
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1010172900/"/>
        <updated>2015-10-10T17:29:00+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1010172900</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;“Support Vector Machine” (SVM) is a supervised machine learning algorithm which can be used for both classification or regression challenges. However,  it is mostly used in classification problems. In this algorithm, we plot each data item as a point in n-dimensional space (where n is number of features you have) with the value of each feature being the value of a particular coordinate. Then, we perform classification by finding the hyper-plane that differentiate the two classes very well.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Game Development with D
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1010152402/"/>
        <updated>2015-10-10T15:24:02+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1010152402</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;D along with the Dgame package allow for quick game prototyping and development, epecially when compared to C++ and its equivalent graphics packages. This tutorial will show you how to create a simple game engine and implementation using the engine.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building a JSON API with Rails 5
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1006081539/"/>
        <updated>2015-10-06T08:15:39+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/1006081539</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Leigh Halliday is a developer at theScore. He writes about Ruby, Rails, and software development on his personal site.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Getting Started with OpenHAB Home Automation on Raspberry Pi
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0929075836/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-29T07:58:36+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0929075836</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;OpenHAB is a mature, open source home automation platform that runs on a variety of hardware and is protocol agnostic, meaning it can connect to nearly any home automation hardware on the market today. If you’ve been frustrated with the number of manufacturer specific apps you need to run just to control your lights, then I’ve got great news for you: OpenHAB is the solution you’ve been looking for – it’s the most flexible smart home hub you’ll ever find.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Software Costs Estimation In Agile Project Management
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0926160454/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-26T16:04:54+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0926160454</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things to do in software development is to determine how long and how much it will take to deliver a new software product. Should it be so hard? The answer is not straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Agari - Leveraging AWS to Build a Scalable Data Pipeline
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0926155959/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-26T15:59:59+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0926155959</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Data-rich companies (e.g. LinkedIn, Facebook, Google, and Twitter) have historically built custom data pipelines over bare metal in custom-designed data centers. In order to meet strict requirements on data security, fault-tolerance, cost control, job scalability, and uptime, they need to closely manage their core technology.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How Agari Uses Airbnb&#39;s Airflow as a Smarter Cron - High Scalability -
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0908084413/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-08T08:44:13+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0908084413</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;This is a guest repost by Siddharth Anand, Data Architect at Agari, on Airbnb’s open source project Airflow, a workflow scheduler for data pipelines. Some think Airflow has a superior approach.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Neural networks and deep learning - free eBook
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907083625/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-07T08:36:25+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907083625</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Neural Networks and Deep Learning is a free online book. The book will teach you about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neural networks, a beautiful biologically-inspired programming paradigm which enables a computer to learn from observational data
Deep learning, a powerful set of techniques for learning in neural networks
Neural networks and deep learning currently provide the best solutions to many problems in image recognition, speech recognition, and natural language processing. This book will teach you many of the core concepts behind neural networks and deep learning.
For more details about the approach taken in the book, see here. Or you can jump directly to Chapter 1 and get started.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>SIMP - NSA security compliance framework
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907082653/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-07T08:26:53+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907082653</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;SIMP is a framework that aims to provide a reasonable combination of security compliance and operational flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of the project is to provide a complete management environment focused on compliance with the various profiles in the SCAP Security Guide Project and industry best practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it is fully capable out of the box, the intent of SIMP is to be molded to your target environment in such a way that deviations are easily identifiable to both Operations Teams and Security Officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time, there are no commercial requirements for the use of SIMP outside of the purchase of Red Hat Enterprise Linux licenses as applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>From Kafka to ZeroMQ for real-time log aggregation
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0905164416/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-05T16:44:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0905164416</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;This post is about ditching Kafka in favor of ZeroMQ, based on a year-long experience of using Kafka for real-time log aggregation in a production setting of Auth0 Webtasks. What, why, and how - read on.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Hello Elixir. Wow.
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904200115/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-04T20:01:15+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904200115</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;I don’t know anything about Elixir, but I very much want to learn it. I like learning new things – I feel it’s required for our industry. It’s easy to feel a twinge of snark about this, I feel that too, every day. But every now and again something comes along and I just find myself getting pulled right in.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Implementing a Neural Network from Scratch - An Introduction
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904195716/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-04T19:57:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904195716</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this post we will implement a simple 3-layer neural network from scratch. We won’t derive all the math that’s required, but I will try to give an intuitive explanation of what we are doing. I will also point to resources for you read up on the details.
Get the code: To follow along, all the code is also available as an iPython notebook on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Creating a Web App From Scratch Using AngularJS and Firebase - Tuts+ Code Tutorials
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0903184803/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-03T18:48:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0903184803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this series, we’ll be using AngularJS and Firebase to create a simple web application from scratch. It will be a simple blogging application where the user can sign in or sign up and publish a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Software Costs Estimation In Agile Project Management
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0902082636/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-02T08:26:36+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0902082636</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things to do in software development is to determine how long and how much it will take to deliver a new software product. Should it be so hard? The answer is not straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Voice controlled PHP apps with API.ai
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901191859/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-01T19:18:59+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901191859</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we’ll be looking into Api.ai, an API that lets us build apps which understand natural language, much like Siri. It can accept either text or speech as input, which it then parses and returns a JSON string that can be interpreted by the code that we write.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How security flaws work: The buffer overflow
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901090330/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-01T09:03:30+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901090330</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;The buffer overflow has long been a feature of the computer security landscape. In fact the first self-propagating Internet worm—1988’s Morris Worm—used a buffer overflow in the Unix finger daemon to spread from machine to machine. Twenty-seven years later, buffer overflows remain a source of problems. Windows infamously revamped its security focus after two buffer overflow-driven exploits in the early 2000s. And just this May, a buffer overflow found in a Linux driver left (potentially) millions of home and small office routers vulnerable to attack.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Linux workstation security checklist
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901085721/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-01T08:57:21+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901085721</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;This is a set of recommendations used by the Linux Foundation for their systems administrators. All of LF employees are remote workers and we use this set of guidelines to ensure that a sysadmin’s system passes core security requirements in order to reduce the risk of it becoming an attack vector against the rest of our infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Integrating Amazon Kinesis, Amazon S3 and Amazon Redshift with Cascading on Amazon EMR
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0828204609/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-28T20:46:09+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0828204609</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;With Amazon Kinesis developers can quickly store, collate and access large, distributed data streams such as access logs, click streams and IoT data in real-time. The question then becomes, how can we access and leverage this data for use in data applications running in Amazon EMR? There are many ways to solve this problem, but the solution should be simple, fault tolerant and highly scalable. In this post I demonstrate a micro-batch system that delivers this solution by processing a simulated real-time data stream using Amazon Kinesis with Cascading on Amazon EMR. We will also join our Amazon Kinesis stream with data residing in a file in Amazon S3 and write our results to Amazon Redshift using cascading-jdbc-redshift which leverages Amazon Redshift’s COPY command.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Sentiment Analysis Using Doc2Vec | Pandamonium
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827183938/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-27T18:39:38+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827183938</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Word2Vec is dope. In short, it takes in a corpus, and churns out vectors for each of those words. What’s so special about these vectors you ask? Well, similar words are near each other. Furthermore, these vectors represent how we use the words. For example, v_man - v_woman is approximately equal to v_king - v_queen, illustrating the relationship that “man is to woman as king is to queen”. This process, in NLP voodoo, is called word embedding. &lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Extending Seven Bridges Genomics with Amazon Redshift and R
</title>
        <link href="https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827081105/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-27T08:11:05+01:00</updated>
        <id>https://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827081105</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>https://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;We will walk through an end-to-end genomics analysis using the Seven Bridges Genomics platform, an AWS advanced technology partner that offers a solution for data scientists looking to analyze large-scale, next-generation, sequencing (NGS) data securely. We will also demonstrate how easy it is to extend this platform to use the additional analytics capabilities offered by AWS. First, we will identify the genetic “variants” in an individual—what makes them unique—and then conduct a comparison of variation across a group of people.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>