<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    

    <title>Direction With Intent</title>
    <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
		<icon>http://directionwithintent.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
    <subtitle>Think Through. Execute.</subtitle>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <updated>2015-07-23T08:45:28+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://directionwithintent.com/</id>
    <author>
			<name>Nuno Valente</name>
			<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
			<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
		</author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>GitHub Special: Data Scientists to Follow &amp;amp; Best Tutorials on GitHub
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723084452/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T08:44:52+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723084452</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t tried this yet, it’s your turn now. I have compiled a list of some awesome Data Scientists on GitHub. In addition, you’ll also find the list of best data science tutorials available on GitHub. Specially for beginners, if don’t know about GitHub, here’s the quick introduction in simple words.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Uncertainty in Real-Time Fraud Detection
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723080420/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T08:04:20+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723080420</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;There are only a few complex event processing (CEP) fraud engines that support all of the varieties of uncertainty that reside in financial environments. Here, RTInsights contributor Ivo Correia discusses the need to support uncertainty—which may constitute a significant line of research and development for CEP engines.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Your PenTest Tools Arsenal InfoGraphic | CTF365 Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723075918/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T07:59:18+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723075918</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Though there are hundreds and hundreds of information security tools and each month we see tens of other that appear, most of responders was focused on a few well established tools. Bellow you have the answers of 871 security professionals that choose to fill in the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Create a character voting app using React, Node.js, MongoDB and Socket.IO
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723074848/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T07:48:48+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723074848</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we are going to build a character voting app (inspired by &lt;em&gt;Facemash&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hot or Not&lt;/em&gt;) for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eveonline.com/&quot;&gt;EVE Online&lt;/a&gt; - a massively multiplayer online game. Be sure to play this awesome soundtrack below to get yourself in the mood for this epicly long tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>System Resource Usage Monitor Forensics
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0722195153/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-22T19:51:53+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0722195153</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Windows 8 operating system has a newly added feature to track system resource usage, specifically process and network metrics over time. Process related information such as process owner, CPU cycles used, data bytes read/written, and network data are continuously recorded by a mechanism called System Resource Usage Monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Snifer/security-cheatsheets
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0722083018/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-22T08:30:18+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0722083018</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;These security cheatsheets are part of a project for the Ethical Hacking and Penetration Testing course offered at the University of Florida. Expanding on the default set of cheatsheets, the purpose of these cheatsheets are to aid penetration testers/CTF participants/security enthusiasts in remembering commands that are useful, but not frequently used.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Under the Hood of Amazon EC2 Container Service - All Things Distributed
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/184215/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-20T18:42:15+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/184215</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In my last post about Amazon EC2 Container Service (Amazon ECS), I discussed the two key components of running modern distributed applications on a cluster:  reliable state management and flexible scheduling. Amazon ECS makes building and running containerized applications simple, but how that happens is what makes Amazon ECS interesting. Today, I want to explore the Amazon ECS architecture and what this architecture enables.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Embrace event-driven computing: Amazon expands DynamoDB with streams, cross-region replication, and database triggers - All Things Distributed
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/010736/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-19T01:07:36+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/010736</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Many happy developers are using DynamoDB to handle trillions of requests every day. I am excited to share with you that today we are expanding DynamoDB with streams, cross-region replication, and database triggers. In this blog post, I will explain how these three new capabilities empower you to build applications with distributed systems architecture and create responsive, reliable, and high-performance applications using DynamoDB that work at any scale.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Designing a Programming Language
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/165510/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-18T16:55:10+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/165510</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Programming languages come in a variety of different paradigms. Even so, there tend to be two main camps along the language front. There are static languages and there are dynamic languages. To avoid too much history and any sort of in-depth analysis, this article will simplify things with a number of assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>50 Beautifully Illustrated Graphics With Tips To Make You A Better Designer &amp;ndash; Design School
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/164118/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-18T16:41:18+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/164118</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Designers illustrate stories for their audience with the application of type, color, images and other graphic features. Like a writer when telling a story, there are specific tips and techniques that designers use to ensure the tone is correct and the messages are being brought to life.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A curated list of awesome Machine Learning frameworks, libraries and software. - Mo-Data. Data made Easy
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183317/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-09T18:33:17+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183317</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Link to Joseph Misiti (click on this link to get to the page with the full set of hyperlinks): &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/josephmisiti/awesome-machine-learning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A curated list of awesome Machine Learning frameworks, libraries and software.&lt;/a&gt; – .&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>DDD for Rails Developers. Part 1: Layered Architecture.
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/093707/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T09:37:07+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/093707</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;There are many kinds of complexity that you have to deal with developing software and different kinds of applications will have very different sets of problems you need to solve. If you are building the next Twitter, scalability and fault-tolerance are the problems you are probably fighting. On the other hand, these problems are almost never an issue when working on enterprise applications. The complex domain is what you tackle when developing enterprise software. Business processes of a lot of companies are far from being trivial. Thus, refining the domain that provides loose coupling and will be flexible and maintainable in the future is extremely hard and requires a lot of practice and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Recognising a Bad User Interface at First Glance | A variety of (dis)information
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080134/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T08:01:34+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080134</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;When I wrote my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hadermann.be/blog/121/enterprise-software-acquisition-whats-missing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, it dawned on me that a trained eye can often spot unfriendly software a mile away.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Arrow – An advanced Kanban board - JAXenter
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080038/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T08:00:38+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080038</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;After his success with the Priority Pyramid, Tomas Rybing is back with another great way to organise your workflow via the Kanban methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Scanning for vulnerabilities in just 10 minutes with VAddy’s simple URL crawler
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/075601/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T07:56:01+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/075601</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;VAddy starts scanning for vulnerabilities after you have registered a test server and crawl data for your site. The crawl data includes URLs and parameters to scan; VAddy’s scanner learns the structure of your site from this information. To register crawl data, you have needed to configure your browser’s proxy settings (IP address and port number) to point to VAddy’s servers and then visit the website you wish to scan.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Start Using Landsat on AWS | AWS Official Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183320/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-06T18:33:20+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183320</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;My colleague Jed Sundwall wrote the guest post below to show you how one of the newest AWS Public Data Sets is being put to use.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Apple has published a great free learn to code course for Swift
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/200803/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-26T20:08:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/200803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Apple has apparently, via some sort of collaboration with a university professor, published last week — during WWDC — a really solid-looking learn-to-code curriculum for Swift that is kind of on iTunes U but that is really on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Neuralnet mlp - mlxtend
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194614/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-25T19:46:14+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194614</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Implementation of a feedforward artificial neural network (multilayer perceptron, MLP). Although the code is fully working and can be used for common classification tasks, this implementation is not geared towards efficiency but clarity – the original code was written for demonstration purposes (a more detailed blog article and step by step walkthrough is going to follow).&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Leaflet: Interactive web maps with R
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194034/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-25T19:40:34+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194034</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that a new package &lt;strong&gt;leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; has been released on CRAN. The R package &lt;strong&gt;leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; is an interface to the JavaScript library &lt;a href=&quot;http://leafletjs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; to create interactive web maps. It was developed on top of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://htmlwidgets.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;htmlwidgets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; framework, which means the maps can be rendered in R Markdown (v2) documents, Shiny apps, and RStudio IDE / the R console. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstudio.github.io/leaflet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://rstudio.github.io/leaflet&lt;/a&gt; for the full documentation. To install the package, run&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Learned to Love to Crash (With Elixir)
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/133158/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-20T13:31:58+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/133158</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;That’s what I kept hearing. To be honest, it’s taken me a while to grok this. It wasn’t until I designed and implemented a few systems with a focus on a &lt;code&gt;Process&lt;/code&gt; based architecture that the philosophy really clicked. Now, it’s core to my thinking and it’s enabled me start writing systems with greater fault tolerant that are more well thought out, with less code.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Understanding Color Psychology for Impactful Web Design - Designmodo
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/191809/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-17T19:18:09+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/191809</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that &lt;strong&gt;color psychology&lt;/strong&gt; is used extensively in all aspects of design. From the colors used on day-to-day grocery items, to brand logos and website design, color is an important element that can convey a specific message to users.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Ultimate Introduction To Agile Project Management
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/195803/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-16T19:58:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/195803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;You’re in charge of delivering your company’s latest and greatest initiative that’s going to change the face of “Widgets International” forever. It’s a software project that’ll engage and enthrall your customers, make your colleague’s lives easier, and make the company millions in revenue. There’s a great deal of anticipation, fervour, excitement, and expectation. You need to get it done as quickly as possible, so your business can start to reap the benefits. The future success of the company depends on you. All eyes are on you. You cannot fail.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Designing For Animation
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085516/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-16T08:55:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085516</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animation&lt;/strong&gt;, like any other facet of the web, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/05/14/functional-ux-design-animations/&quot;&gt;must&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/11/18/the-state-of-animation-2014/&quot;&gt;be&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/09/14/the-guide-to-css-animation-principles-and-examples/&quot;&gt;designed&lt;/a&gt;. As web developers, we think about the effects of typography, layout, interaction, and shifting viewports, but when incorporating animation we have another factor to consider: time.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building a Binary Classification Model with Amazon Machine Learning and Amazon Redshift
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/182301/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-15T18:23:01+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/182301</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Many decisions in life are binary, answered either Yes or No. Many business problems also have binary answers. For example: “Is this transaction fraudulent?”, “Is this customer going to buy that product?”, or “Is this user going to churn?” In machine learning, this is called a binary classification problem. Many business decisions can be enhanced by accurately predicting the answer to a binary question.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Writing a full-text search engine using Bloom filters - Stavros&amp;#39; Stuff
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085031/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-29T08:50:31+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085031</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;A few minutes ago I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6867102&quot;&gt;a Hacker News post&lt;/a&gt; that detailed a method of adding search to your static site. As you probably know, adding search to a static site is a bit tricky, because you can’t just send the query to a server and have the server process it and return the results. If you want full-text search, you have to implement something like an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inverted_index&quot;&gt;inverted index&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>