<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    

    <title>Direction With Intent</title>
    <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
		<icon>http://directionwithintent.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
    <subtitle>Think Through. Execute.</subtitle>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <updated>2015-07-20T08:29:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://directionwithintent.com/</id>
    <author>
			<name>Nuno Valente</name>
			<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
			<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
		</author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>Embrace event-driven computing: Amazon expands DynamoDB with streams, cross-region replication, and database triggers - All Things Distributed
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/010736/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-19T01:07:36+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/010736</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Many happy developers are using DynamoDB to handle trillions of requests every day. I am excited to share with you that today we are expanding DynamoDB with streams, cross-region replication, and database triggers. In this blog post, I will explain how these three new capabilities empower you to build applications with distributed systems architecture and create responsive, reliable, and high-performance applications using DynamoDB that work at any scale.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Designing a Programming Language
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/165510/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-18T16:55:10+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/165510</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Programming languages come in a variety of different paradigms. Even so, there tend to be two main camps along the language front. There are static languages and there are dynamic languages. To avoid too much history and any sort of in-depth analysis, this article will simplify things with a number of assumptions. One assumption we will make which might not always hold true is that programs written in static languages are compiled to machine code, while programs that are written in dynamic languages run in an interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>50 Beautifully Illustrated Graphics With Tips To Make You A Better Designer &amp;ndash; Design School
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/164118/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-18T16:41:18+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/164118</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Designers illustrate stories for their audience with the application of type, color, images and other graphic features. Like a writer when telling a story, there are specific tips and techniques that designers use to ensure the tone is correct and the messages are being brought to life.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A curated list of awesome Machine Learning frameworks, libraries and software. - Mo-Data. Data made Easy
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183317/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-09T18:33:17+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183317</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Link to Joseph Misiti (click on this link to get to the page with the full set of hyperlinks): &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/josephmisiti/awesome-machine-learning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A curated list of awesome Machine Learning frameworks, libraries and software.&lt;/a&gt; – .&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>DDD for Rails Developers. Part 1: Layered Architecture.
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/093707/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T09:37:07+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/093707</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;There are many kinds of complexity that you have to deal with developing software and different kinds of applications will have very different sets of problems you need to solve. If you are building the next Twitter, scalability and fault-tolerance are the problems you are probably fighting. On the other hand, these problems are almost never an issue when working on enterprise applications. The complex domain is what you tackle when developing enterprise software. Business processes of a lot of companies are far from being trivial. Thus, refining the domain that provides loose coupling and will be flexible and maintainable in the future is extremely hard and requires a lot of practice and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Recognising a Bad User Interface at First Glance | A variety of (dis)information
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080134/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T08:01:34+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080134</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;When I wrote my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hadermann.be/blog/121/enterprise-software-acquisition-whats-missing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, it dawned on me that a trained eye can often spot unfriendly software a mile away.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Arrow – An advanced Kanban board - JAXenter
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080038/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T08:00:38+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080038</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;After his success with the Priority Pyramid, Tomas Rybing is back with another great way to organise your workflow via the Kanban methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Scanning for vulnerabilities in just 10 minutes with VAddy’s simple URL crawler
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/075601/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T07:56:01+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/075601</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;VAddy starts scanning for vulnerabilities after you have registered a test server and crawl data for your site. The crawl data includes URLs and parameters to scan; VAddy’s scanner learns the structure of your site from this information. To register crawl data, you have needed to configure your browser’s proxy settings (IP address and port number) to point to VAddy’s servers and then visit the website you wish to scan.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Start Using Landsat on AWS | AWS Official Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183320/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-06T18:33:20+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183320</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;My colleague Jed Sundwall wrote the guest post below to show you how one of the newest AWS Public Data Sets is being put to use.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Apple has published a great free learn to code course for Swift
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/200803/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-26T20:08:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/200803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Apple has apparently, via some sort of collaboration with a university professor, published last week — during WWDC — a really solid-looking learn-to-code curriculum for Swift that is kind of on iTunes U but that is really on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Neuralnet mlp - mlxtend
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194614/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-25T19:46:14+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194614</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Implementation of a feedforward artificial neural network (multilayer perceptron, MLP). Although the code is fully working and can be used for common classification tasks, this implementation is not geared towards efficiency but clarity – the original code was written for demonstration purposes (a more detailed blog article and step by step walkthrough is going to follow).&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Leaflet: Interactive web maps with R
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194034/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-25T19:40:34+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194034</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that a new package &lt;strong&gt;leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; has been released on CRAN. The R package &lt;strong&gt;leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; is an interface to the JavaScript library &lt;a href=&quot;http://leafletjs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; to create interactive web maps. It was developed on top of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://htmlwidgets.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;htmlwidgets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; framework, which means the maps can be rendered in R Markdown (v2) documents, Shiny apps, and RStudio IDE / the R console. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstudio.github.io/leaflet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://rstudio.github.io/leaflet&lt;/a&gt; for the full documentation. To install the package, run&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Learned to Love to Crash (With Elixir)
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/133158/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-20T13:31:58+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/133158</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;That’s what I kept hearing. To be honest, it’s taken me a while to grok this. It wasn’t until I designed and implemented a few systems with a focus on a &lt;code&gt;Process&lt;/code&gt; based architecture that the philosophy really clicked. Now, it’s core to my thinking and it’s enabled me start writing systems with greater fault tolerant that are more well thought out, with less code.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Understanding Color Psychology for Impactful Web Design - Designmodo
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/191809/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-17T19:18:09+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/191809</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that &lt;strong&gt;color psychology&lt;/strong&gt; is used extensively in all aspects of design. From the colors used on day-to-day grocery items, to brand logos and website design, color is an important element that can convey a specific message to users.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Ultimate Introduction To Agile Project Management
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/195803/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-16T19:58:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/195803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;You’re in charge of delivering your company’s latest and greatest initiative that’s going to change the face of “Widgets International” forever. It’s a software project that’ll engage and enthrall your customers, make your colleague’s lives easier, and make the company millions in revenue. There’s a great deal of anticipation, fervour, excitement, and expectation. You need to get it done as quickly as possible, so your business can start to reap the benefits. The future success of the company depends on you. All eyes are on you. You cannot fail.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Designing For Animation
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085516/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-16T08:55:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085516</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animation&lt;/strong&gt;, like any other facet of the web, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/05/14/functional-ux-design-animations/&quot;&gt;must&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/11/18/the-state-of-animation-2014/&quot;&gt;be&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/09/14/the-guide-to-css-animation-principles-and-examples/&quot;&gt;designed&lt;/a&gt;. As web developers, we think about the effects of typography, layout, interaction, and shifting viewports, but when incorporating animation we have another factor to consider: time.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building a Binary Classification Model with Amazon Machine Learning and Amazon Redshift
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/182301/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-15T18:23:01+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/182301</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Many decisions in life are binary, answered either Yes or No. Many business problems also have binary answers. For example: “Is this transaction fraudulent?”, “Is this customer going to buy that product?”, or “Is this user going to churn?” In machine learning, this is called a binary classification problem. Many business decisions can be enhanced by accurately predicting the answer to a binary question.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Writing a full-text search engine using Bloom filters - Stavros&amp;#39; Stuff
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085031/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-29T08:50:31+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085031</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;A few minutes ago I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6867102&quot;&gt;a Hacker News post&lt;/a&gt; that detailed a method of adding search to your static site. As you probably know, adding search to a static site is a bit tricky, because you can’t just send the query to a server and have the server process it and return the results. If you want full-text search, you have to implement something like an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inverted_index&quot;&gt;inverted index&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Why White Space Is Crucial To UX Design | Co.Design | business + design
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084653/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-29T08:46:53+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084653</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;White space can be broken down into four elements: visual white space (space surrounding graphics, icons, and images); layout white space (margins, paddings, and gutters); text white space (spacing between lines and spacing between letters); and content white space (space separating columns of text).&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building Modern Web Applications with AngularJS and Play Framework
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/201232/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-27T20:12:32+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/201232</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Choosing the right tool for the right purpose goes a long way, especially when it comes to building modern web applications. A lot of us are familiar with AngularJS and how easy it makes developing robust web application front-ends. Although many will argue against the use of this popular web framework, it certainly has plenty to offer and can be &lt;a href=&quot;/angular-js/a-step-by-step-guide-to-your-first-angularjs-app&quot;&gt;an appropriate choice&lt;/a&gt; for a wide array of needs. On the other hand, the components that you use on the back-end will dictate a lot about the web application’s performance, as they have influence on the overall user experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playframework.com/&quot;&gt;Play&lt;/a&gt; is a high velocity web framework for Java and Scala. It is based on a lightweight, stateless, web-friendly architecture and follows MVC patterns and principles similar to Rails and Django.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>AWS re:Invent 2014 | (PFC306) Performance Tuning Amazon EC2 Instances - YouTube
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085506/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-19T08:55:06+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085506</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Netflix tunes Amazon EC2 instances for maximum performance. In this session, you learn how Netflix configures the fastest possible EC2 instances, while reducing latency outliers. This session explores the various Xen modes (e.g., HVM, PV, etc.) and how they are optimized for different workloads. Hear how Netflix chooses Linux kernel versions based on desired performance characteristics and receive a firsthand look at how they set kernel tunables, including hugepages. You also hear about Netflix’s use of SR-IOV to enable enhanced networking and their approach to observability, which can exonerate EC2 issues and direct attention back to application performance.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Forex Algorithmic Trading: A Practical Tale for Engineers
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/235018/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-18T23:50:18+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/235018</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;As you may know, the Foreign Exchange (Forex) market is used for trading between currency pairs. But you might not be aware that it’s the most liquid market in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building Context Aware Apps | Toptal</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/150655/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-17T15:06:55+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/150655</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Mobile phone usage across the globe is constantly increasing. As of 2013, around 73% of Internet users consumed content via a mobile device and this percentage is expected to reach &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statista.com/topics/779/mobile-internet/&quot;&gt;close to 90%&lt;/a&gt; by 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Why most unit testing is waste</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/113158/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-17T11:31:58+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/113158</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Unit testing was a staple of the FORTRAN days, when a
function was a function and was sometimes worthy of functional
testing. Computers computed, and functions and procedures
represented units of computation. In those days the dominant
design process composed complex external functionality from
smaller chunks, which in turn orchestrated yet smaller chunks,
and so on down to the level of well-understood primitives. Each
layer supported the layers above it. You actually stood a good
chance that you could trace the functionality of the things at the
bottom, called functions and procedures, to the requirements
that gave rise to them out at the human interface. There was
hope that a good designer could understand a given function’s
business purpose. And it was possible, at least in well-structured
code, to reason about the calling tree. You could mentally
simulate code execution in a code review.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How Bad UX Makes Users Blame Themselves - UXPin</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084716/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-15T08:47:16+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084716</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;When things go wrong, we want to know why as quickly and easily (but maybe not truthfully) as possible. But when technology is thrown into the mix, the problems are more complex. Our perceptions change. When something goes wrong with a user interface, the questions don’t always have easy answers.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>