<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    

    <title>Direction With Intent</title>
    <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
		<icon>http://directionwithintent.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
    <subtitle>Think Through. Execute.</subtitle>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <updated>2015-08-03T19:00:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://directionwithintent.com/</id>
    <author>
			<name>Nuno Valente</name>
			<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
			<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
		</author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>Announcing Pulsar: Real-time Analytics at Scale
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803190003/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T19:00:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803190003</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce Pulsar, an open-source, real-time analytics platform and stream processing framework. Pulsar can be used to collect and process user and business events in real time, providing key insights and enabling systems to react to user activities within seconds. In addition to real-time sessionization and multi-dimensional metrics aggregation over time windows, Pulsar uses a SQL-like event processing language to offer custom stream creation through data enrichment, mutation, and filtering. Pulsar scales to a million events per second with high availability. It can be easily integrated with metrics stores like Cassandra and Druid.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Full-Text Search Algorithm in Javascript - Burak Kanber&#39;s Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803185637/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T18:56:37+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803185637</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Full-text search, unlike most of the topics in this machine learning series, is a problem that most web developers have encountered at some point in their daily work. A client asks you to put a search field somewhere, and you write some SQL along the lines of WHERE title LIKE %:query%. It’s convincing at first, but then a few days later the client calls you and claims that “search is broken!”&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>District Data Labs - Modern Methods for Sentiment Analysis
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803173554/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T17:35:54+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803173554</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Sentiment analysis is a common application of Natural Language Processing (NLP) methodologies, particularly classification, whose goal is to extract the emotional content in text. In this way, sentiment analysis can be seen as a method to quantify qualitative data with some sentiment score. While sentiment is largely subjective, sentiment quantification has enjoyed many useful implementations, such as businesses gaining understanding about consumer reactions to a product, or detecting hateful speech in online comments.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Implementing and analyzing online experiments
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803113230/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T11:32:30+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803113230</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Randomized experiments are the gold standard for understanding and quantifying causal relationships. This talk is divided into two parts corresponding to before and after the experiment is run.  In the first section, we discuss how to design and implement online experiments using PlanOut, an open-source toolkit for advanced online experimentation used at Facebook. We will show how basic “A/B tests”, within-subjects designs, as well as more sophisticated experiments can be implemented.  In the second section, we cover methods to estimate causal quantities of interest and construct appropriate confidence intervals. Particular attention will be given to scalable methods suitable for “big data”, including working with weighted data and clustered bootstrapping.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Spin up a Docker dev/test Environment in 60 Minutes or Less - Blog - Joyent
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803112555/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T11:25:55+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803112555</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;I was a Joyent customer before I joined as an employee. I discovered Joyent’s infrastructure automation solutions while looking for a hybrid cloud solution that would allow me to run dev and test code in a private environment and production in a public cloud with a global presence. The Triton Elastic Container Infrastructure (formerly SmartDataCenter or SDC7) that powers Joyent’s public cloud is open source and available for anybody to install to power private clouds, allowing users to enjoy the same platform everywhere. It’s free for use as open source, but enterprises of all sizes take advantage of our commercial support offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>CloudWatch Logs Subscription Consumer + Elasticsearch + Kibana Dashboards | AWS Official Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803112050/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T11:20:50+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803112050</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Many of the things that I blog about lately seem to involve interesting combinations of two or more AWS services and today’s post is no exception. Before I dig in, I’d like to briefly introduce all of the services that I plan to name-drop later in this post. Some of this will be review material, but I do like to make sure that every one of my posts makes sense to someone who knows little or nothing about AWS.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Deep Learning Sentiment Analysis for Movie Reviews using Neo4j
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803110316/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T11:03:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803110316</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Sentiment analysis uses natural language processing to extract features of a text that relate to subjective information found in source materials.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Intro to WebGL with Three.js
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803012838/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T01:28:38+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803012838</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;JavaScript API for rendering interactive 2D and 3D graphics inside an HTML canvas element.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Hack Like a Pro: Metasploit for the Aspiring Hacker, Part 1 (Primer &amp;amp; Overview)
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803010009/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T01:00:09+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803010009</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;I have written many tutorials on hacking using Metasploit, including leaving no evidence behind and exploring the inner architecture. Also, there are my Metasploit cheat sheets for commands and hacking scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Forex Trading Diary #1 - Automated Forex Trading with the OANDA API - QuantStart
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803004917/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-03T00:49:17+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0803004917</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;I previously mentioned in the QuantStart: 2014 In Review article that I would be spending some of 2015 writing about automated forex trading.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Spark SQL: Relational Data Processing in Spark
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802233242/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-02T23:32:42+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802233242</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Spark SQL is a new module in Apache Spark that integrates relational processing with Spark’s functional programming API. Built on our experience with Shark, Spark SQL lets Spark programmers leverage the benefits of relational processing (e.g., declarative queries and optimized storage), and lets SQL users call complex analytics libraries in Spark (e.g., machine learning).&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Lynis 2.1.1 - Security Auditing Tool for Unix/Linux Systems
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802205940/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-02T20:59:40+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802205940</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Lynis is an open source security auditing tool. Commonly used by system administrators, security professionals and auditors, to evaluate the security defenses of their Linux/Unix based systems. It runs on the host itself, so it can perform very extensive security scans.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A Neural Network in 11 lines of Python (Part 1) - i am trask
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802204952/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-02T20:49:52+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802204952</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Summary:&lt;/b&gt; I learn best with toy code that I can play with. This tutorial teaches backpropagation via a very simple toy example, a short python implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Getting started with Kafka in node.js with the Confluent REST Proxy
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802161916/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-02T16:19:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802161916</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Previously, I posted about Confluent’s open source Kafka REST Proxy, which provides easy access to a Kafka cluster from any language. That post focused on the motivation, low-level examples, and implementation of the REST Proxy. In this post, I want to follow up by showing how quickly you can create a wrapper for your favorite language and use that wrapper to build applications. With the REST Proxy, you only need a couple of hours to go from zero to comprehensive Kafka support for your preferred language.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Introduction To Monte Carlo Methods
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802151616/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-02T15:16:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0802151616</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going to keep this tutorial light on math, because the goal is just to give a general understanding. Monte Carlo methods originated from the Manhattan Project, as a way to simulate the distance neutrons would travel through through various materials [1]. Ideas using sampling had been around for a little while, but they took off…&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Creating your own private botnet for scanning.
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0731081142/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-31T08:11:42+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0731081142</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Often while scanning a network with nmap or other similar tools, at some point a NIDS or firewall will detect and block me.  This is irritating.  I wondered, what would happen if I could route my scans/attacks through a series of proxy servers. &lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Making Apache Kafka Elastic With Apache Mesos
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0725160249/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-25T16:02:49+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0725160249</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Apache Kafka is a distributed, high-throughput, low-latency publish-subscribe messaging system. Since it was open-sourced in 2011, Apache Kafka has been adopted widely across the industry at web companies like LinkedIn, Netflix, and Uber, as well as traditional enterprises like Cisco and Goldman Sachs.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Product Development - The Hierarchy of Needs
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0724133025/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-24T13:30:25+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0724133025</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;But what is valuable for my customers and users? Some time ago it was much easier to decide which features should be built into the next release - the business people told us. In those days software was mainly created for use in business or science. Nowadays software has become an integrated part of everyday life for just about everybody. The question what is most valuable could be answered much easier if customers and users are part of a well-known business context. But what may be valuable to customers whom I do not even know in an unstructured and completely individualized market?&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Algorithmia Blog -Mining Product Hunt: Detecting Vote-Rings - Algorithmia Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723160943/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T16:09:43+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723160943</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;We like showcasing practical algorithms on interesting datasets. This post is part of a series of posts that explore some algorithms by applying them on the Product Hunt dataset. Since this is the first of the series, we’ll start with how we acquired the data, and then drill down on our approach for the vote-ring problem.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Binary pattern matching in Elixir with PNG parsing example
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723155314/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T15:53:14+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723155314</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Dealing with binary data has always been a pickle in OOP language. Pattern matching is very fundemental to Elixir making the functions much more descriptive. I was very pleased to see that the pattern matching was not just limited to tuple, list etc. but extended to binary data as well.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Architecting Backend for a Social&amp;nbsp;Product - High Scalability -
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723150811/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T15:08:11+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723150811</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is aimed towards taking you through key architectural decisions which will make a social application a true next generation social product. The proposed changes addresses following attributes; a) availability b) reliability c) scalability d) performance and flexibility towards extensions (not modifications)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>GitHub Special: Data Scientists to Follow &amp;amp; Best Tutorials on GitHub
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723084452/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T08:44:52+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723084452</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t tried this yet, it’s your turn now. I have compiled a list of some awesome Data Scientists on GitHub. In addition, you’ll also find the list of best data science tutorials available on GitHub. Specially for beginners, if don’t know about GitHub, here’s the quick introduction in simple words.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Uncertainty in Real-Time Fraud Detection
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723080420/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T08:04:20+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723080420</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;There are only a few complex event processing (CEP) fraud engines that support all of the varieties of uncertainty that reside in financial environments. Here, RTInsights contributor Ivo Correia discusses the need to support uncertainty—which may constitute a significant line of research and development for CEP engines.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Your PenTest Tools Arsenal InfoGraphic | CTF365 Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723075918/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T07:59:18+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723075918</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Though there are hundreds and hundreds of information security tools and each month we see tens of other that appear, most of responders was focused on a few well established tools. Bellow you have the answers of 871 security professionals that choose to fill in the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Create a character voting app using React, Node.js, MongoDB and Socket.IO
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723074848/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-23T07:48:48+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0723074848</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we are going to build a character voting app (inspired by &lt;em&gt;Facemash&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hot or Not&lt;/em&gt;) for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eveonline.com/&quot;&gt;EVE Online&lt;/a&gt; - a massively multiplayer online game. Be sure to play this awesome soundtrack below to get yourself in the mood for this epicly long tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>