<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    

    <title>Direction With Intent</title>
    <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
		<icon>http://directionwithintent.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
    <subtitle>Think Through. Execute.</subtitle>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <updated>2015-07-07T08:05:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://directionwithintent.com/</id>
    <author>
			<name>Nuno Valente</name>
			<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
			<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
		</author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>Recognising a Bad User Interface at First Glance | A variety of (dis)information
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080134/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T08:01:34+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080134</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;When I wrote my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hadermann.be/blog/121/enterprise-software-acquisition-whats-missing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, it dawned on me that a trained eye can often spot unfriendly software a mile away.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Arrow – An advanced Kanban board - JAXenter
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080038/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T08:00:38+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/080038</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;After his success with the Priority Pyramid, Tomas Rybing is back with another great way to organise your workflow via the Kanban methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Scanning for vulnerabilities in just 10 minutes with VAddy’s simple URL crawler
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/075601/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-07T07:56:01+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/075601</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;VAddy starts scanning for vulnerabilities after you have registered a test server and crawl data for your site. The crawl data includes URLs and parameters to scan; VAddy’s scanner learns the structure of your site from this information. To register crawl data, you have needed to configure your browser’s proxy settings (IP address and port number) to point to VAddy’s servers and then visit the website you wish to scan.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Start Using Landsat on AWS | AWS Official Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183320/"/>
        <updated>2015-07-06T18:33:20+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/183320</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;My colleague Jed Sundwall wrote the guest post below to show you how one of the newest AWS Public Data Sets is being put to use.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Apple has published a great free learn to code course for Swift
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/200803/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-26T20:08:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/200803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Apple has apparently, via some sort of collaboration with a university professor, published last week — during WWDC — a really solid-looking learn-to-code curriculum for Swift that is kind of on iTunes U but that is really on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Neuralnet mlp - mlxtend
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194614/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-25T19:46:14+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194614</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Implementation of a feedforward artificial neural network (multilayer perceptron, MLP). Although the code is fully working and can be used for common classification tasks, this implementation is not geared towards efficiency but clarity – the original code was written for demonstration purposes (a more detailed blog article and step by step walkthrough is going to follow).&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Leaflet: Interactive web maps with R
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194034/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-25T19:40:34+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/194034</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that a new package &lt;strong&gt;leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; has been released on CRAN. The R package &lt;strong&gt;leaflet&lt;/strong&gt; is an interface to the JavaScript library &lt;a href=&quot;http://leafletjs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; to create interactive web maps. It was developed on top of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://htmlwidgets.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;htmlwidgets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; framework, which means the maps can be rendered in R Markdown (v2) documents, Shiny apps, and RStudio IDE / the R console. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstudio.github.io/leaflet&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://rstudio.github.io/leaflet&lt;/a&gt; for the full documentation. To install the package, run&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Learned to Love to Crash (With Elixir)
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/133158/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-20T13:31:58+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/133158</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;That’s what I kept hearing. To be honest, it’s taken me a while to grok this. It wasn’t until I designed and implemented a few systems with a focus on a &lt;code&gt;Process&lt;/code&gt; based architecture that the philosophy really clicked. Now, it’s core to my thinking and it’s enabled me start writing systems with greater fault tolerant that are more well thought out, with less code.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Understanding Color Psychology for Impactful Web Design - Designmodo
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/191809/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-17T19:18:09+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/191809</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that &lt;strong&gt;color psychology&lt;/strong&gt; is used extensively in all aspects of design. From the colors used on day-to-day grocery items, to brand logos and website design, color is an important element that can convey a specific message to users.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>The Ultimate Introduction To Agile Project Management
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/195803/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-16T19:58:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/195803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;You’re in charge of delivering your company’s latest and greatest initiative that’s going to change the face of “Widgets International” forever. It’s a software project that’ll engage and enthrall your customers, make your colleague’s lives easier, and make the company millions in revenue. There’s a great deal of anticipation, fervour, excitement, and expectation. You need to get it done as quickly as possible, so your business can start to reap the benefits. The future success of the company depends on you. All eyes are on you. You cannot fail.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Designing For Animation
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085516/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-16T08:55:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085516</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animation&lt;/strong&gt;, like any other facet of the web, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2015/05/14/functional-ux-design-animations/&quot;&gt;must&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2014/11/18/the-state-of-animation-2014/&quot;&gt;be&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/09/14/the-guide-to-css-animation-principles-and-examples/&quot;&gt;designed&lt;/a&gt;. As web developers, we think about the effects of typography, layout, interaction, and shifting viewports, but when incorporating animation we have another factor to consider: time.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building a Binary Classification Model with Amazon Machine Learning and Amazon Redshift
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/182301/"/>
        <updated>2015-06-15T18:23:01+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/182301</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Many decisions in life are binary, answered either Yes or No. Many business problems also have binary answers. For example: “Is this transaction fraudulent?”, “Is this customer going to buy that product?”, or “Is this user going to churn?” In machine learning, this is called a binary classification problem. Many business decisions can be enhanced by accurately predicting the answer to a binary question.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Writing a full-text search engine using Bloom filters - Stavros&amp;#39; Stuff
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085031/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-29T08:50:31+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085031</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;A few minutes ago I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6867102&quot;&gt;a Hacker News post&lt;/a&gt; that detailed a method of adding search to your static site. As you probably know, adding search to a static site is a bit tricky, because you can’t just send the query to a server and have the server process it and return the results. If you want full-text search, you have to implement something like an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inverted_index&quot;&gt;inverted index&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Why White Space Is Crucial To UX Design | Co.Design | business + design
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084653/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-29T08:46:53+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084653</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;White space can be broken down into four elements: visual white space (space surrounding graphics, icons, and images); layout white space (margins, paddings, and gutters); text white space (spacing between lines and spacing between letters); and content white space (space separating columns of text).&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building Modern Web Applications with AngularJS and Play Framework
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/201232/"/>
        <updated>2015-05-27T20:12:32+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/201232</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Choosing the right tool for the right purpose goes a long way, especially when it comes to building modern web applications. A lot of us are familiar with AngularJS and how easy it makes developing robust web application front-ends. Although many will argue against the use of this popular web framework, it certainly has plenty to offer and can be &lt;a href=&quot;/angular-js/a-step-by-step-guide-to-your-first-angularjs-app&quot;&gt;an appropriate choice&lt;/a&gt; for a wide array of needs. On the other hand, the components that you use on the back-end will dictate a lot about the web application’s performance, as they have influence on the overall user experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.playframework.com/&quot;&gt;Play&lt;/a&gt; is a high velocity web framework for Java and Scala. It is based on a lightweight, stateless, web-friendly architecture and follows MVC patterns and principles similar to Rails and Django.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>AWS re:Invent 2014 | (PFC306) Performance Tuning Amazon EC2 Instances - YouTube
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085506/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-19T08:55:06+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/085506</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Netflix tunes Amazon EC2 instances for maximum performance. In this session, you learn how Netflix configures the fastest possible EC2 instances, while reducing latency outliers. This session explores the various Xen modes (e.g., HVM, PV, etc.) and how they are optimized for different workloads. Hear how Netflix chooses Linux kernel versions based on desired performance characteristics and receive a firsthand look at how they set kernel tunables, including hugepages. You also hear about Netflix’s use of SR-IOV to enable enhanced networking and their approach to observability, which can exonerate EC2 issues and direct attention back to application performance.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Forex Algorithmic Trading: A Practical Tale for Engineers
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/235018/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-18T23:50:18+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/235018</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;As you may know, the Foreign Exchange (Forex) market is used for trading between currency pairs. But you might not be aware that it’s the most liquid market in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building Context Aware Apps | Toptal</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/150655/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-17T15:06:55+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/150655</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Mobile phone usage across the globe is constantly increasing. As of 2013, around 73% of Internet users consumed content via a mobile device and this percentage is expected to reach &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.statista.com/topics/779/mobile-internet/&quot;&gt;close to 90%&lt;/a&gt; by 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Why most unit testing is waste</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/113158/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-17T11:31:58+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/113158</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Unit testing was a staple of the FORTRAN days, when a
function was a function and was sometimes worthy of functional
testing. Computers computed, and functions and procedures
represented units of computation. In those days the dominant
design process composed complex external functionality from
smaller chunks, which in turn orchestrated yet smaller chunks,
and so on down to the level of well-understood primitives. Each
layer supported the layers above it. You actually stood a good
chance that you could trace the functionality of the things at the
bottom, called functions and procedures, to the requirements
that gave rise to them out at the human interface. There was
hope that a good designer could understand a given function’s
business purpose. And it was possible, at least in well-structured
code, to reason about the calling tree. You could mentally
simulate code execution in a code review.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How Bad UX Makes Users Blame Themselves - UXPin</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084716/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-15T08:47:16+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084716</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;When things go wrong, we want to know why as quickly and easily (but maybe not truthfully) as possible. But when technology is thrown into the mix, the problems are more complex. Our perceptions change. When something goes wrong with a user interface, the questions don’t always have easy answers.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Meaningful transitions - Animation - Google design guidelines</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084905/"/>
        <updated>2015-01-14T08:49:05+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/084905</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it is difficult for a user to know where to look or understand how an element got from point A to point B. Carefully choreographed motion design can effectively guide the user’s attention and focus through multiple steps of a process or procedure, avoid confusion when layouts change or elements are rearranged, and improve the overall beauty of the experience. Motion design should serve a functional purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Implement a Real-time, Sliding-Window Application Using Amazon Kinesis and Apache Storm</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/193131/"/>
        <updated>2014-12-28T16:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/193131</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Streams of data are becoming ubiquitous today – clickstreams, log streams, event streams, and more. The need for real-time processing of high-volume data streams is pushing the limits of traditional data processing infrastructures. Building a clickstream monitoring system, for example, where data is in the form of a continuous clickstream rather than discrete data sets, requires the use of continuous processing rather than ad-hoc, one-time queries.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Zero to 353 Pages: Bringing My Web Book to Print and eBook</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/192834-share/"/>
        <updated>2014-12-28T15:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/192834-share</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;It’s a funny feeling to spend nearly six years making something and then finally hold it in your hand. It’s simultaneously, “This is it!” and “Is this it?” How can it be so small when it feels like such a big piece of my life?
Most of that time, the book existed entirely on the web. It was less “book” and more “book-length manuscript that you can read with your browser”. The web site is still the book’s real home in some ways. If you want to know more about game programming and software architecture, take a look. You can read the whole thing online, for free, because I love you.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Binaural Sound with the Web Audio API</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/163232-share/"/>
        <updated>2014-12-28T13:30:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/163232-share</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Head-related transfer functions describe the cues we receive that enable us to determine the direction a sound arrives from. We only have two ears. To be able to determine the direction the sound arrives from in 3D, our brain has to use all the information it can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the sound will often arrive at the other ear with a small delay. Also, there will often be a difference in the sound level at one ear, as compared to the other (especially at high frequencies). But, additionally, there is a ton of information available for our brain to use. Our shoulders reflect sound. Sound reflects and diffracts around our external ears (pinna). As our features, such as the shape of our pinna, are individual, so is the way our brain perceives sound in 3D.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>PEG that data - Part 1</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/programming/peg_that_data_1/"/>
        <updated>2014-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/programming/peg_that_data_1</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	&lt;img src=&quot;http://directionwithintent.com/images/peg_1600x800.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        	&lt;p&gt;In simple (maybe simplistic) terms, Parsing Expression Grammars or just PEGs are formalisms that describe languages, in the form of a set of rules that can be converted to string recognition mechanisms to parse the aforementioned languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could spend some paragraphs, poorly describing PEGs, but I’ll leave this to a better-suited place for this subject: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsing_expression_grammar&quot;&gt;Wikipedia - PEG&lt;/a&gt;. At the time of this article writing, Wikipedia holds a very well put description of PEGs and their nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If after reading that link you still feel a bit confuse with this matter maybe you should need to deepen your knowledge about programming languages but fear not. Don’t invest in a Computer Science course right now and bear with me for a while. I’ll want to begin by building the equivalent of the usual Hello World program as a PEG. Actually we can start by building a PEG that recognizes a “Hello World” string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complying with the rules that we’ve learned in the previously supplied link, let’s build our PEG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ExpStart := &quot;Hello World&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a pointless exercise indeed. The start expression only waits for input that matches exactly “Hello World” and that’s it.
At this point, you maybe thinking that I’m in an exercise of spending time of my innocent readers but don’t get fooled by the simplicity of our first PEG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s build up on this PEG and accept more subjects for our greeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ExpStart := &quot;Hello&quot; Space Subject
Space    := &quot; &quot;   
Subject  := &quot;World&quot; | &quot;Solar System&quot; | &quot;Galaxy&quot; | &quot;Universe&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While keeping this exercise very easy, we’ve introduced a rule that after a standard “Hello” greeting expects a white space and after that a Subject. This Subject can be one of the choices at right member of the Subject rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our augmented PEG can recognize strings such as “Hello World”, “Hello Solar System”, “Hello Galaxy” or “Hello Universe”. Far beyond from those boring Hello World programs don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless if one wants to greet all the Subjects one needs four strings. What a waste of time and quotes. Let’s improve our PEG so that it can accept all of the Hello greetings in a single string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ExpStart := &quot;Hello&quot; Space Subject &quot;.&quot; (Space ExpStart)?
Space    := &quot; &quot;
Subject  := &quot;World&quot; | &quot;Solar System&quot; | &quot;Galaxy&quot; | &quot;Universe&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit more complicated to read, but still we can follow easily the rules to build our greeting string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The build path is the same one than our previous PEG. Our starting expression waits for a “Hello” string followed by a Space and after that for a Subject. Add a “.” at the end of a string and our PEG would happily accept our saluting.
The difference now is that we’ve defined a group that may or may not exist afterward (No Schroedinger no…cho choooo. Out of here.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group &lt;code&gt;(Space ExpStart)?&lt;/code&gt; means that one can add another Space and follow that by our ExpStart in a recursive fashion. Now we can accept well-articulated greetings such as: “Hello World. Hello Solar System”, “Hello World. Hello Solar System. Hello Galaxy.” or even “Hello World. Hello Solar System. Hello Galaxy. Hello Universe.”. If one wants we can repeat this string as long our keyboard complies and our PEG will accept this expression until your RAM cannot swap more space to disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it would be interesting to see our expressions being actually validated somewhere instead of relying only in a theoretical example. At the time of writing this article the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pegjs.majda.cz&quot;&gt;PEG.js&lt;/a&gt; project page had a great online version of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pegjs.majda.cz/online&quot;&gt;PEG parser&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PEG library provided by this project page will be used in our following articles so we might as well test it right away with our Hello World samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just copy our last grammar expressions, converted below to the requested syntax, to the box “1 - Write your PEG.js grammar”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ExpStart = &quot;Hello&quot; Space Subject &quot;.&quot; (Space ExpStart)?
Space    = &quot; &quot;
Subject  = &quot;World&quot; / &quot;Solar System&quot; / &quot;Galaxy&quot; / &quot;Universe&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all goes well you will receive a green “Parser built successfully” message below the grammar input box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test our grammar just copy one of our accepted test strings in to the box “2 - Test generated parser with some input”. Let’s jump to the biggest one, “Hello World. Hello Solar System. Hello Galaxy. Hello Universe.” and once again we hope to be presented with a green “Input parsed successfully.” box above. As a bonus, we can inspect the resulting syntax tree in a JSON array format provided in “Output”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s end our first PEG exercise. I’ll recommend a thorough reading of the PEG.js library syntax and options for our next article where we will dive deep into a interesting problem while building more than a syntax validator.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>