<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    

    <title>Direction With Intent</title>
    <generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
		<icon>http://directionwithintent.com/apple-touch-icon-precomposed.png</icon>
    <subtitle>Think Through. Execute.</subtitle>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <updated>2015-09-26T16:01:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://directionwithintent.com/</id>
    <author>
			<name>Nuno Valente</name>
			<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
			<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
		</author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>Agari - Leveraging AWS to Build a Scalable Data Pipeline
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0926155959/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-26T15:59:59+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0926155959</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Data-rich companies (e.g. LinkedIn, Facebook, Google, and Twitter) have historically built custom data pipelines over bare metal in custom-designed data centers. In order to meet strict requirements on data security, fault-tolerance, cost control, job scalability, and uptime, they need to closely manage their core technology.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How Agari Uses Airbnb&#39;s Airflow as a Smarter Cron - High Scalability -
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0908084413/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-08T08:44:13+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0908084413</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;This is a guest repost by Siddharth Anand, Data Architect at Agari, on Airbnb’s open source project Airflow, a workflow scheduler for data pipelines. Some think Airflow has a superior approach.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Neural networks and deep learning - free eBook
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907083625/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-07T08:36:25+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907083625</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Neural Networks and Deep Learning is a free online book. The book will teach you about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neural networks, a beautiful biologically-inspired programming paradigm which enables a computer to learn from observational data
Deep learning, a powerful set of techniques for learning in neural networks
Neural networks and deep learning currently provide the best solutions to many problems in image recognition, speech recognition, and natural language processing. This book will teach you many of the core concepts behind neural networks and deep learning.
For more details about the approach taken in the book, see here. Or you can jump directly to Chapter 1 and get started.&lt;/p&gt;


        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>SIMP - NSA security compliance framework
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907082653/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-07T08:26:53+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0907082653</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;SIMP is a framework that aims to provide a reasonable combination of security compliance and operational flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal of the project is to provide a complete management environment focused on compliance with the various profiles in the SCAP Security Guide Project and industry best practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it is fully capable out of the box, the intent of SIMP is to be molded to your target environment in such a way that deviations are easily identifiable to both Operations Teams and Security Officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time, there are no commercial requirements for the use of SIMP outside of the purchase of Red Hat Enterprise Linux licenses as applicable.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>From Kafka to ZeroMQ for real-time log aggregation
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0905164416/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-05T16:44:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0905164416</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;This post is about ditching Kafka in favor of ZeroMQ, based on a year-long experience of using Kafka for real-time log aggregation in a production setting of Auth0 Webtasks. What, why, and how - read on.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Hello Elixir. Wow.
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904200115/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-04T20:01:15+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904200115</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;I don’t know anything about Elixir, but I very much want to learn it. I like learning new things – I feel it’s required for our industry. It’s easy to feel a twinge of snark about this, I feel that too, every day. But every now and again something comes along and I just find myself getting pulled right in.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Implementing a Neural Network from Scratch - An Introduction
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904195716/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-04T19:57:16+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0904195716</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this post we will implement a simple 3-layer neural network from scratch. We won’t derive all the math that’s required, but I will try to give an intuitive explanation of what we are doing. I will also point to resources for you read up on the details.
Get the code: To follow along, all the code is also available as an iPython notebook on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Creating a Web App From Scratch Using AngularJS and Firebase - Tuts+ Code Tutorials
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0903184803/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-03T18:48:03+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0903184803</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this series, we’ll be using AngularJS and Firebase to create a simple web application from scratch. It will be a simple blogging application where the user can sign in or sign up and publish a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Software Costs Estimation In Agile Project Management
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0902082636/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-02T08:26:36+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0902082636</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things to do in software development is to determine how long and how much it will take to deliver a new software product. Should it be so hard? The answer is not straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Voice controlled PHP apps with API.ai
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901191859/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-01T19:18:59+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901191859</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial we’ll be looking into Api.ai, an API that lets us build apps which understand natural language, much like Siri. It can accept either text or speech as input, which it then parses and returns a JSON string that can be interpreted by the code that we write.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How security flaws work: The buffer overflow
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901090330/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-01T09:03:30+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901090330</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;The buffer overflow has long been a feature of the computer security landscape. In fact the first self-propagating Internet worm—1988’s Morris Worm—used a buffer overflow in the Unix finger daemon to spread from machine to machine. Twenty-seven years later, buffer overflows remain a source of problems. Windows infamously revamped its security focus after two buffer overflow-driven exploits in the early 2000s. And just this May, a buffer overflow found in a Linux driver left (potentially) millions of home and small office routers vulnerable to attack.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Linux workstation security checklist
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901085721/"/>
        <updated>2015-09-01T08:57:21+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0901085721</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;This is a set of recommendations used by the Linux Foundation for their systems administrators. All of LF employees are remote workers and we use this set of guidelines to ensure that a sysadmin’s system passes core security requirements in order to reduce the risk of it becoming an attack vector against the rest of our infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Integrating Amazon Kinesis, Amazon S3 and Amazon Redshift with Cascading on Amazon EMR
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0828204609/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-28T20:46:09+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0828204609</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;With Amazon Kinesis developers can quickly store, collate and access large, distributed data streams such as access logs, click streams and IoT data in real-time. The question then becomes, how can we access and leverage this data for use in data applications running in Amazon EMR? There are many ways to solve this problem, but the solution should be simple, fault tolerant and highly scalable. In this post I demonstrate a micro-batch system that delivers this solution by processing a simulated real-time data stream using Amazon Kinesis with Cascading on Amazon EMR. We will also join our Amazon Kinesis stream with data residing in a file in Amazon S3 and write our results to Amazon Redshift using cascading-jdbc-redshift which leverages Amazon Redshift’s COPY command.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Sentiment Analysis Using Doc2Vec | Pandamonium
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827183938/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-27T18:39:38+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827183938</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Word2Vec is dope. In short, it takes in a corpus, and churns out vectors for each of those words. What’s so special about these vectors you ask? Well, similar words are near each other. Furthermore, these vectors represent how we use the words. For example, v_man - v_woman is approximately equal to v_king - v_queen, illustrating the relationship that “man is to woman as king is to queen”. This process, in NLP voodoo, is called word embedding. &lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Extending Seven Bridges Genomics with Amazon Redshift and R
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827081105/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-27T08:11:05+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0827081105</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;We will walk through an end-to-end genomics analysis using the Seven Bridges Genomics platform, an AWS advanced technology partner that offers a solution for data scientists looking to analyze large-scale, next-generation, sequencing (NGS) data securely. We will also demonstrate how easy it is to extend this platform to use the additional analytics capabilities offered by AWS. First, we will identify the genetic “variants” in an individual—what makes them unique—and then conduct a comparison of variation across a group of people.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Deploy Your Rails App to AWS
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0825080638/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-25T08:06:38+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0825080638</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;As developers, we are usually concerned about the development part of any application. We don’t think much about the deployment part as we consider it to be a responsibility of the SysAdmins. But many times, we don’t have a dedicated SysAdmin available, so we have to put on the SysAdmin hat and get things done. There are many options to deploy your Rails application. Today, I will cover how to deploy a Rails application to Amazon Web Services (AWS) using Capistrano.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How does a relational database work - Coding Geek
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0825080126/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-25T08:01:26+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0825080126</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;When it comes to relational databases, I can’t help thinking that something is missing. They’re used everywhere. There are many different databases: from the small and useful SQLite to the powerful Teradata. But, there are only a few articles that explain how a database works. You can google by yourself “how does a relational database work” to see how few results there are. Moreover, those articles are short. Now, if you look for the last trendy technologies (Big Data, NoSQL or JavaScript), you’ll find more in-depth articles explaining how they work.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Getting Started with Docker: Simplifying Devops
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0824080425/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-24T08:04:25+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0824080425</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;If you like whales, or are simply interested in quick and painless continuous delivery of your software to production, then I invite you to read this introductory Docker Tutorial. Everything seems to indicate that software containers are the future of IT, so let’s go for a quick dip with the container whales Moby Dock and Molly.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Building an MVC Application with Spring Framework: A Beginner&#39;s Tutorial
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0824080224/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-24T08:02:24+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0824080224</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Java is often said to be too complicated and to take too long to build simple applications. Nonetheless, Java provides a stable platform with a very mature ecosystem around it, which makes it a wonderful option for developing robust software.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Eventually Consistent Transactions
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0820081348/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-20T08:13:48+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0820081348</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Eventually Consistent Transactions - Burckhardt et al. 2012 There&#39;s another ECOOP&#39;15 paper I&#39;d like to cover this week - Burckhardt et al.&#39;s &quot;Global Sequence Protocol.&quot; But that paper builds on the notion of Cloud Types (similar in spirit to CRDTs, and not something I&#39;ve personally come across before), which in turn builds on work on…&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Kaizen: Get a Little Better Each Day | The Art of Manliness
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0820080936/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-20T08:09:36+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0820080936</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;The Kaizen approach to self-improvement completely circumvents the unproductive ups and downs all too common to the quest. By breaking down big, overwhelming goals into super small, discrete pieces, Kaizen encourages action. The small successes you experience with your baby steps feed on each other and start building some momentum, which leads to taking bigger and bigger actions.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Understanding Bayes: A Look at the Likelihood
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0819080646/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-19T08:06:46+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0819080646</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Much of the discussion in psychology surrounding Bayesian inference focuses on priors. Should we embrace priors, or should we be skeptical? When are Bayesian methods sensitive to specification of the prior, and when do the data effectively overwhelm it? Should we use context specific prior distributions or should we use general defaults? These are all great questions and great discussions to be having.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>How a Kalman filter works, in pictures | Bzarg
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0819075645/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-19T07:56:45+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0819075645</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly few software engineers and scientists seem to know about it, and that makes me sad because it is such a general and powerful tool for combining information in the presence of uncertainty. At times its ability to extract accurate information seems almost magical and if it sounds like I’m talking this up too much, then take a look at this previously posted video where I demonstrate a Kalman filter figuring out the orientation of a free-floating body by looking at its velocity. Totally neat!&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>A beginner&#39;s guide to understanding UX design
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0818083419/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-18T08:34:19+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0818083419</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of working on your conversion optimization and landing page optimization, understanding UX design is essential. As you know, we write a lot about the user, the single visitor that arrives on your site or landing page and needs to be triggered and helped around. UX design helps make sure that during this process the most important person isn’t left out of the mix: The user.&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Let&#39;s Build A Simple Interpreter. Part 1. - Ruslan&#39;s Blog
</title>
        <link href="http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0818082855/"/>
        <updated>2015-08-18T08:28:55+01:00</updated>
        <id>http://directionwithintent.com/shares/0818082855</id>
        <author>
					<name>Nuno Valente</name>
					<uri>http://directionwithintent.com/</uri>
					<email>nuno.valente@gmail.com</email>
				</author>
        <content type="html">
        	
        	&lt;p&gt;“If you don’t know how compilers work, then you don’t know how computers work. If you’re not 100% sure whether you know how compilers work, then you don’t know how they work.” — Steve Yegge There you have it. Think about it. It doesn’t really matter …&lt;/p&gt;

        </content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>